<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leisure on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/categories/leisure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leisure on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/categories/leisure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading &#34;Pride and Prejudice&#34; in my Thirties</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/reading-pride-and-prejudice-in-my-thirties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/reading-pride-and-prejudice-in-my-thirties/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I received &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; as an audiobook from my local library, and I&amp;rsquo;m very glad. Even if I had managed to have no difficulty getting into it this time around, I only have a limited time for engaging with reading from printed books and this allowed me to go through a much longer work in a reasonable amount of time. I spend a lot of time on the road in this phase of my life, so audiobooks are a good option for me. If I had been reading the classic on paper I would have had to devote several months to reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been avoiding &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; for far too long. It was difficult to get into. The writing is very involved, and the book starts an a very slow roll. Much of the action in the book is indirectly implied. There are layers of conversational intrigue that take a lot of time to build up. It took a while to tune my senses to pay attention to the right parts of the story to track the action. I think listening to audio helped me work through to the point where all of that build up started to pay off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; is essentially a &amp;ldquo;Victorian decorum thriller.&amp;rdquo; I really enjoyed Austen&amp;rsquo;s wry sense of humor. Because I had never been successful at truly getting into the book before now, I was caught off-guard by this playfulness from Austen. It did get literally laugh-out-loud funny. I found myself chuckling several times! It was definitely unexpected given my prior experience with the novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the primary points the novel makes is the difference between being good and being friendly. This is definitely a useful lesson to remember. We often mistake friendliness and politeness with goodness. As I have aged I have become increasingly wary of charisma and what it can hide. The novel was a good reminder of that lesson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I really enjoyed about the &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; was the window it gave into Victorian life. It portrays a much more pragmatic perspective on life and marriage than is generally idealized today. Class and the trappings of class are incredibly important. One of the things that I noticed about the novel is how the servant class is erased almost entirely from the work. I know that there were a number of people working all around the main characters, but in Austen&amp;rsquo;s work they were less than faceless – they were invisible, they often were not even mentioned in passing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more practical note, I was surprised at Wickham&amp;rsquo;s ability to desert the Army without any real reproach. After my own years of military service, this blew me out of the water. At first I thought that this was an oversight, but after looking up some of the history of military service in this era I learned that it was fairly common for officers to enter and leave the service with some degree of fluidity. This happened in no small part because a relatively large roll of officers was needed in order to support a full command structure during a time of war. When a need emerged to conscript a large number of soldiers into service, there would be no time to identify and train up a large contingent of senior leadership in addition. To accommodate this need the rolls contained a large number of officers – many more than regular daily duties required – and so these officers often spent time both in and out of service, serving and advancing in both civilian pursuits and a military career as it suited them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, I enjoyed the book quite immensely on my first time through it successfully. It comes highly recommended, though an audio version may be the best for readers like myself, especially on a first reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-my-twenties&#34;&gt;In my Twenties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my twenties my re-reading focused on books that I had read in High School. Since I had tried to read &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; recreationally, but had never finished it or been required to read it, Austen&amp;rsquo;s classic didn&amp;rsquo;t pass through my hands in my Twenties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-my-teens&#34;&gt;In my Teens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to read &lt;em&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/em&gt; in my teen years, while I was in High School, but I found it slow and uninteresting. I never really got into the book, and I soon put it down. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t required reading in any of my High School classes. I had only tried to read it because I had heard so much about it. My own experiences with it at this young age were not sufficiently exciting to draw me in for recreational reading when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t required of me, so I ended up giving up on it. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until years later when I picked it up again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading &#34;The Call of the Wild&#34; in my Thirties</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/reading-the-call-of-the-wild-in-my-thirties/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/reading-the-call-of-the-wild-in-my-thirties/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I reserved the book from the library and when I picked it up I noticed that it had been shelved in the &amp;ldquo;Juvenile&amp;rdquo; section. I was surprised at how well-suited the book is for young readers. I had remembered it as a &amp;ldquo;very adult&amp;rdquo; sort of book, but that was not my experience as a reader at 33. I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been surprised that a book considered appropriate for 6th graders at the time that I read it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be as adult as I remembered it, but I was surprised nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What London calls the &amp;ldquo;The Law of Club and Fang&amp;rdquo; reminds me of my time in the Army. Exhaustion, stress, and necessity chip away at the trappings and niceties that are built into our lives so we can ignore the fact that we are little more than bald, feeble chimps playing dress-up. In the end, &lt;em&gt;Call of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; is a love note to savagery. Buck descends from perfectly tame, through cruel hands to a life of hard work, and finally into being untamed, and is all the happier for it. Humans pass through Buck&amp;rsquo;s life as casually as he passes through theirs. Buck respects most humans, but only grows to love one. It is the loss of this last man that cuts the final tie keeping Buck in the civilized world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brutality is a consistent theme throughout the book. Men are cruel with one another, and with their animals. Paradoxically, the book presents the humane treatment of animals both as a luxury and as essential to survival. Treating the dogs roughly is presented as a requirement for life. The sled has to cross the North, and stopping could mean death. At the same time, treating them so badly they can no longer work becomes a hazard as well. Overloading the sled and under-rationing the dogs can also leave you stranded. In the end, the book distinguishes between roughness and cruelty in a way that I think is useful while also being interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was bothered at the way that the book ended. Apart from the minor foreshadowing from the arrow, there was no real treatment of natives at all. It&amp;rsquo;s unsurprising that they are entirely ignored in the novel until they become useful for the narrative, then they swarm in, deus ex machina, to bring on the denouement of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;London&amp;rsquo;s novel is an example of a time period that held a strong fascination for the &amp;ldquo;noble savage.&amp;rdquo; Even now we idolize nature. I am reminded how, in the Biblical narrative, God creates the world then gives mankind dominion over the world, entrusting his creation to Adam. Modern society has ceased to view humanity as a caretaker which lives as a part of the natural world, replacing this view with the view that nature is innately good and entirely separate from humanity. This view believes that removing humanity entirely from ecosystems is the best option. They are wrong. It isn&amp;rsquo;t best (or even possible, really) to remove humanity from nature. It would be best to recognize yet again our place as a part of a natural world. Humans change ecosystems, which can be bad, but we certainly aren&amp;rsquo;t the only animal that do so and these changes are not negative by necessity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-my-twenties&#34;&gt;In my Twenties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my twenties my re-reading focused on books that I had read in High School only, so I did not re-read this book. In fact, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even remember reading this book at that age, or that &lt;em&gt;The Call of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;White Fang&lt;/em&gt; were even different books. I added this book to my list for The Decades Project after my first pass through the list, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t read the book in my Twenties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-my-teens&#34;&gt;In my Teens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first read &lt;em&gt;The Call of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; in my very early teens. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the exact year, but I believe it was around the age of thirteen. Honestly, it may have even been a few years before that first year of my teens. I remember the book fondly. In fact, my memories of the book blend together with &lt;em&gt;White Fang&lt;/em&gt; a book with similar subjects by the same author which I read shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I greatly enjoyed the book. It was perfectly situated to capture the attention of a middle school kid just graduating from &lt;em&gt;Hardy Boys&lt;/em&gt; mysteries. I read the book quickly, primarily focusing on the story. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I took much from the book&amp;rsquo;s themes, but did enjoy it. As an early reader, the story was definitely the most compelling part of the novel for me, and the story was engaging for a boy around my age who had grown up with dogs in the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book was probably my first significant encounter with character dialogue written in dialect. It must have been a good introduction because I didn&amp;rsquo;t remember the dialogue being written in dialect at all. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I had it as an introduction for the more difficult to decipher dialect writing used by Twain and other authors that I read later in my teens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading &#34;Of Mice and Men&#34; in my Thirties</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/reading-of-mice-and-men-in-my-thirties/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/reading-of-mice-and-men-in-my-thirties/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have enjoyed this novel every single time I have read it. It is a fast and easy read, and so amazingly tightly written. I keep finding new and interesting things from it at every age. The lessons that I learn seem to have similar themes, but they are always different lessens. I also love Steinbeck as a writer. This is the first time that I have read Steinbeck knowing that, as a career Academic, I am a writer too. His writing is inspirationally good – which isn&amp;rsquo;t really all that surprising once you realize he is a Nobel laureate. As someone who now has much more experience as a writer than my younger self, it is clear that he has spent a lot of time on rewriting and editing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current American climate, and my career in Academia, has really made me view &lt;em&gt;Of Mice and Men&lt;/em&gt; through a more feminist lens this time around. I think the paper has some very important things to say about masculinity and how masculinity is constructed. The two themes in this area that jumped out at me the most were 1) the performance of masculinity in the face of failure and 2) the fear of being powerless in the face of accusations from women. Fundamentally, both of these themes are about powerlessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also struck by the universality of yearning for an idyllic futures. We all tell ourselves these quiet lies about how some day we will arrive and then things will be much easier. &amp;ldquo;Things will be better when&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; – but they never are. As a man just arriving at the end of graduate schooling and starting in my career as an Assistant Professor, I can sympathize with looking forward to how much better life will be, even knowing that nothing can ever be as good as you can dream it will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed how cinematic Steinbeck was in his description of the scenery. The locations in which the events of the story occur almost become their own characters. They are often left alone on the &amp;ldquo;stage&amp;rdquo; at the beginning and end of chapters. Of course, this helps to personify the place and pull the reader in, but it is even more interesting in how it emphasizes the transient nature of George and Lenny&amp;rsquo;s existence. The persistence of the setting without the main characters present also draws attention to how inconsequential George and Lenny are. Their appearance and disappearance has minor impacts on the world around them, but shortly after they are gone the world soon returns to business as usual – they have not brought about any lasting changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also struck by his skillful use of foreshadowing. Everything that is in the story serves a function and establishes the facts the story continues to come back to later. In fact, the only place where I noticed an exception to this was when we traveled into Lenny&amp;rsquo;s imaginary world near the end of the novel. This sequence was so out of place that it caught me entirely off guard. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember noticing it before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-my-twenties&#34;&gt;In my Twenties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my twenties I read the novel for the second time. It was shortly after I graduated from college, within the first few years of being in the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; and before I went back to graduate school. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed the first time that Steinbeck had been awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature. this was the first time that I read a novel aware that the author had been awarded the Nobel. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it made a difference in how I perceived the book or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story really touched me in my twenties. I found that I identified with George quite a bit. Throughout my school years, especially in Junior High, I had a number of friends who had more than the usual social and/or intellectual challenges. I understood what it was like to try to help someone understand social expectations or wrestle with unintended consequences, much as George does for Lenny throughout the novel. I don&amp;rsquo;t remember making this personal connection the first time I read the novel; perhaps I needed some distance to notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also appreciated Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s signature style more in my twenties than in my teens. At this age I could recognize the amount of effort and drafting that goes into crafting a novel without any unnecessary words. I still thought of myself as a characteristically terse writer and I thought of Steinbeck as an ideal to be striven for, though I engaged in essentially none of the draft work that is necessary to accomplish the style well. At this age I usually edited while I wrote and thought of my writing as complete right after the first time through. I often wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even proofread, which is more than a little embarrassing looking back on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-my-teens&#34;&gt;In my Teens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only have hazy memories of this book from my teen years. I remember reading it in High School, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t assigned reading in any of my courses. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how or why I picked it up, but it is a shockingly fast read and well worth the time if, for no other reason, the cultural fluency it bought me. There are many allusions to this book throughout popular culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only previous experience with Steinbeck was &lt;em&gt;The Red Pony&lt;/em&gt;, which had been required reading back in Junior High. I remember Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s stark masculine style feeling forced and inauthentic to me in &lt;em&gt;The Red Pony&lt;/em&gt;, but in &lt;em&gt;Of Mice and Men&lt;/em&gt; it rang true. I was struck at the time by the way Steinbeck&amp;rsquo;s masculine style of writing fit with the subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found in Steinbeck a kindred spirit. I had often been critiqued by teachers for my writing being too brief. I often struggled to make papers reach their required lengths. Reading Steinbeck felt like vindication that I could be a good writer. It was only later that I would realize how much writing, revision, and editing it takes to produce such tightly written prose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work-life Balance</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/work-life-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/work-life-balance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have been seeing and hearing more from my friends, acquaintances, and even total strangers about &amp;ldquo;work-life balance.&amp;rdquo; It has really been setting me off. Sometimes I have very strong opinions about relatively minor things. At least, they seem like minor things to other people. &amp;ldquo;Work-life balance&amp;rdquo; is exactly one of these things. I am bothered because the choice of words in the phrase is fundamentally incorrect, but I&amp;rsquo;m even more bothered because of what this improper word choice reveals about our culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-words-are-wrong&#34;&gt;The Words are Wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any true curmudgeon, I have a huge problem with the choice of terms here. The choice of terms in &amp;ldquo;work-life balance&amp;rdquo; carries a lot of assumptions with it that I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to tacitly endorse by using the phrase. The opposite of work is not life. I don&amp;rsquo;t stop being alive when I am at work. Even when I had a terrible job in the kitchen at a Papa John&amp;rsquo;s restaurant in High School, I was definitely still alive. The fact is that work is part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were looking for the proper words, I would probably pick leisure, or relaxation. These are what we&amp;rsquo;re talking about anyway, right? I mean, I know a lot of parents of young children who work, and they have problems with work-life balance even when they are working less than people without children, because people caring for young children have essentially &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; leisure time. That non-work time is all filled up with keeping other humans alive and agonizing that you aren&amp;rsquo;t keeping them alive perfectly enough to keep up with their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final word is just as bad. &amp;ldquo;Balance&amp;rdquo; carries a lot of baggage. It implies that these two extremes must be actively managed, which makes sense until you start thinking about &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; is supposed to be doing that management. In nearly every usage of the phrase that I have seen, the responsibility to balance these two goals is presented as belonging to the individual only, and not to any employer or to society. At best the employer is presented as an enabler of &amp;ldquo;work-life balance,&amp;rdquo; not as its champion. Discussions around achieving &amp;ldquo;work-life balance&amp;rdquo; typically involve things like having flexible hours or working from home. Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: you can&amp;rsquo;t achieve balance without changing the load. If many people in your industry are having problems with work-life balance, it is &lt;em&gt;not a flexibility problem,&lt;/em&gt; it is a work load problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;word-choice-matters&#34;&gt;Word Choice Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, if this were just an issue of poor word choice, the curmudgeon in me would complain, but I would just move on. But something more is going on here. The phrase &amp;ldquo;work-life balance&amp;rdquo; places these two ideas at opposite ends of a dialectic tension, which serves to draw hard lines around work in ways that we often take for granted because they are common in modernized economies. The truth is that these hard lines are largely an exception from the perspective of human history. The homestead was the site of a majority of work for most of recorded human existence. Even when work didn&amp;rsquo;t occur in the family residence, the family often spent time at the place of work. The separation of work and the rest of our lives is both artificial and recent. It is also, I think, harmful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
