<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workflow on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workflow on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Semester Lessons - 2015F</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/end-of-semester-lessons-2015f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/end-of-semester-lessons-2015f/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At the end of every semester I find that there are several things that I want to file away as important lessons for the future. I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I&amp;rsquo;ll use a categorical breakdown in the future, but I have broken down my list this semester into general lessons, lessons about teaching, and lessons about writing. They are, for lack of any better scheme, in alphabetical order. Here is my list for this semester:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general&#34;&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be discouraged when you fall short of your expectations – accept any degree of improvement.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you aren&amp;rsquo;t able to live up to your initial ambitious plans. As long as you are doing better, to any degree, then you are successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on setting up good systems, not just having goals.&lt;/strong&gt; Goals are fantastic and useful, but they can also become a myopic focus that causes you to miss other great opportunities. It is just as important to know when NOT to use goals as it is to know how to set good goals. Often, it is the system you set up to achieve the goal that is actually important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching&#34;&gt;Teaching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have projects build on one another.&lt;/strong&gt; I have used similar strategies in the past, but this semester really underlined for me how important and beneficial this can be for students, especially in classes like presentational speaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detailed emails are a waste of time – put that information somewhere other people can see it.&lt;/strong&gt; The information that you would put into an email, while potentially accessible forever, is almost certainly destined for obscurity. If what you are saying requires a lot of detail, then you need to find a better place to put it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I work best when I write in big chunks, AND ALSO write a little bit every day.&lt;/strong&gt; I find that writing a very small amount on my active project (dissertation) every day complements the writing that I do on dedicated writing days. It keeps the paper fresh in my mind and makes the big days much more productive. It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt that these small days add up over time to real progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being determined can be an obstacle to success – give up and work on something else.&lt;/strong&gt; If I am having trouble writing on one section of my dissertation, the worst thing I can do is keep bashing my head against the wall trying to force it to work. It&amp;rsquo;s OK to not be ready to work on a section yet. Just pivot, pick a different part of the problem, and drive on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define an actual writing process and framework.&lt;/strong&gt; Some writers tend to be verbose, I tend not to say enough. I became much more productive when I set a word-count goal for my dissertation. Then I had to figure out how to budget those words into chapters. Within each chapter I have had to budget it into sections. Defining a structure and targets as a framework has made me much more productive, because it lets me know that, even if I feel like I am done, I&amp;rsquo;m not done yet. In addition, I now have defined stages of the writing process that I track for each section. Now I know that my paper sections will go from &amp;ldquo;To-Do&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;First Draft&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Revised Draft&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Final Draft.&amp;rdquo; I cannot stress enough how important these features have become to my writing process. They are especially important tools for me when working on other projects in collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Friday Roundup</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/adding-a-friday-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/adding-a-friday-roundup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t done as much work on my dissertation over the summer up until this point as I had hoped that I would, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad. I needed some time to decompress and it has been hard to focus on work when so many more important social changes are coursing through the country. It is hard to focus on the importance of my small corner of academia when so many innocent (or at least not sufficiently guilty) people are being literally shot in the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the face of justice so poorly dispensed throughout the United States and media coverage of these tragedies which is nearly as poor, I know that I do have to refocus on advancing my own career as the new semester approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-am-i-adding-a-friday-roundup&#34;&gt;Why am I adding a Friday Roundup?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working on the dissertation for awhile. I have been following a pretty good piece of advice that I got fairly early in the process. &amp;ldquo;If you want to be an academic, you will have to first be a writer.&amp;rdquo; This has lead me to do a lot of reading about what kinds of tips I can find for how to be a better writer. I have read many, but the one which is relevant to this post is that the best way to become good at something is to do it a lot—if you are worried that you are not a very good writer, then the best thing you can do for your writing is to do a lot more of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that vein, these posts are serving to help me keep track of what I am doing, where I have been focused over the last week, where I am currently planning on going over the next week, and so forth. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty enthusiastic about my chances of success, to be honest. I think they will help quite a bit. In order to keep them from taking my focus away from the projects that I am supposed to be focusing on, I am strictly limiting the time that I spend on them and, as a direct consequence, the amount of editing and proofreading that I do. In short, to whomever does read these roundup posts, please excuse the inevitable poor writing and grammatical/typing errors—these pieces are not intended to be polished final products, they are working documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading back over an article in Communication Theory (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-2885.1992.tb00031.x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Babrow, 1992&lt;/a&gt;) on Problematic Integration. The piece discusses the importance of communication (by which he seems to mean interpersonal communication) in the experience of integration difficulties. I am curious how perspectives on communication by other types of actors fits into the theory. This is something that I plan to look into over the next week as I try to position my piece in the larger framework of research in the fields of Communication and Education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why this Website?</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/why-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/why-this-website/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My adviser tells me that I am a &amp;ldquo;systems thinker.&amp;rdquo; She isn&amp;rsquo;t the first one to notice this – I know that she is right. I am constantly trying to optimize and improve the systems I use in my daily life. I notice when things aren&amp;rsquo;t working, and I &lt;strike&gt;obsess over&lt;/strike&gt; often think about ways to improve those processes. In fact, this can be quite a bit of a burden, because it means that I am constantly exposed to one of my greatest temptations to procrastination, and it quickly becomes self-reinforcing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I notice something about my workflow that isn&amp;rsquo;t working as well as it could.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I research, brainstorm and test ways to improve my workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I notice that I&amp;rsquo;m not being very productive (because I&amp;rsquo;m not working).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat from step 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way I have found to counter this process is to find ways to accomplish multiple objectives at once, preferably by building on what I am already doing. This website is a part of that process. I have been having trouble working on my dissertation for quite some time now. I know that I need to be making progress, but it just isn&amp;rsquo;t working out for me. As a communication professional, I believe that I need a strong understanding of programming, web design and web development in general. I also need to know about writing for the Internet, because the Internet has become the primary place of consuming the written word. Finally, it is important to me to maintain my own online presence. I am envisioning that this website will help me to accomplish all of these goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-on-the-dissertation&#34;&gt;Working on the Dissertation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my intention to post regularly about my progress on my dissertation. I don&amp;rsquo;t yet fully know what this will look like, but I do plan write posts about topics within the dissertation. This mimics the way that some classes require small, frequent assignments that can eventually yield much of the raw material in a final project. I may also post short descriptions, summaries, or reactions to pieces that I read. A lot of this is still up in the air, but what is important to me is that I derive benefit toward the dissertation and toward my eventual employment from working on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-web-design-and-web-development&#34;&gt;Programming, Web Design and Web Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Communication professional, and as a knowledge worker generally, I believe it is important to understand how the Internet works. I spend a significant amount of time working with a computer, which is one of the most powerful tools that humans have ever invented. It seems like if I don&amp;rsquo;t learn how to use it effectively, I will have squandered an opportunity to be fantastic at what I do. I already do much more of these things than the average graduate student does, but I believe the payoff is worth the effort. These tools are powerful, and they are changing the world. It is, in my opinion, worth the time spent to learn how to use them well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-for-the-internet&#34;&gt;Writing for the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing for an online audience is hard. I no longer know what students are taught in High School – it has been too long since I was there – but I have not been impressed by my students&amp;rsquo; writing skills. It seems that there is an over-emphasis on one particular genre of writing, which I find troubling. The majority of students who leave high school and college are not likely to engage in very much of the type of writing that they have been taught to produce in high school and college. This is a shame. Students are not generally taught to use non-verbal elements of writing, such as layout, text styles, images, and other things which help engage readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maintaining-an-online-presence&#34;&gt;Maintaining an Online Presence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As knowledge workers, it is becoming increasingly important for academics to have an online presence. If I want to engage people outside the &amp;ldquo;Ivory Tower&amp;rdquo; of academia, then I will need to be accessible. Maintaining an online presence allows me to engage with others and to be find-able. As I continue in the job market, I am hopeful that it may also help me to find the type of job that I want.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
