<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rant on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rant on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Students, Stop Telling me you Won&#39;t be in Class</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/students-stop-telling-me-you-wont-be-in-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/students-stop-telling-me-you-wont-be-in-class/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Every semester I get emails from students that bother me. Every teacher has different preferences. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect students to have mine memorized. Even so, I still find some especially annoying. The one that has been bothering me this week is the &amp;ldquo;hey, I won&amp;rsquo;t be in class, just so you know&amp;rdquo; email. I get it, I just don&amp;rsquo;t care—unless you make it &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; problem too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-get-it&#34;&gt;I Get It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was an undergraduate student too. I remember, and I understand. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect my class to always be your top priority, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me if it isn&amp;rsquo;t. Most traditional college students are new to adulthood, and I remember being new to adulthood myself. Being an adult almost always means juggling a variety of responsibilities and having to pick which ones are the most important at any given time. Sometimes you will have to prioritize your other classes. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to me what your reason is. If it is important enough to you to miss class, then it is important to &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, and that is what matters. It isn&amp;rsquo;t my place to judge your reasons for not being in class. I get it, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-don-t-care&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong—I care about you as a person. The thing is, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect me one way or another if you are in class. I don&amp;rsquo;t plan my classes around your presence, and I don&amp;rsquo;t wait to start class until you get there. I do the same thing whether you are there or not, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to me if you will be in class. Heck, as a faceblind person, I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even notice that you weren&amp;rsquo;t there except for in classes where I take attendance (and even then I still struggle to connect your name with who you actually are anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;except-when-you-make-it-my-problem-too&#34;&gt;Except When You Make it &lt;em&gt;My&lt;/em&gt; Problem Too&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does bother me is when you want to prioritize for free. When you trade off one priority for another, there is always a cost. I just want you to handle it like an adult. You have plenty of classmates to get information from about the class that you missed, so don&amp;rsquo;t ask me what you missed. Course policies for attendance, missed deadlines, and missing coursework were all detailed in the course documents you have had access to since the beginning of the semester. Be an adult and accept the outcomes of your actions—they should not be a surprise to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain times when basic human compassion means you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be exempted from the costs of missing a class. Fortunately, the vast majority of these instances are already covered under university policies for things like grief, illness, military service, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work-life Balance</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/work-life-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/work-life-balance/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have been seeing and hearing more from my friends, acquaintances, and even total strangers about &amp;ldquo;work-life balance.&amp;rdquo; It has really been setting me off. Sometimes I have very strong opinions about relatively minor things. At least, they seem like minor things to other people. &amp;ldquo;Work-life balance&amp;rdquo; is exactly one of these things. I am bothered because the choice of words in the phrase is fundamentally incorrect, but I&amp;rsquo;m even more bothered because of what this improper word choice reveals about our culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-words-are-wrong&#34;&gt;The Words are Wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any true curmudgeon, I have a huge problem with the choice of terms here. The choice of terms in &amp;ldquo;work-life balance&amp;rdquo; carries a lot of assumptions with it that I&amp;rsquo;m not willing to tacitly endorse by using the phrase. The opposite of work is not life. I don&amp;rsquo;t stop being alive when I am at work. Even when I had a terrible job in the kitchen at a Papa John&amp;rsquo;s restaurant in High School, I was definitely still alive. The fact is that work is part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were looking for the proper words, I would probably pick leisure, or relaxation. These are what we&amp;rsquo;re talking about anyway, right? I mean, I know a lot of parents of young children who work, and they have problems with work-life balance even when they are working less than people without children, because people caring for young children have essentially &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; leisure time. That non-work time is all filled up with keeping other humans alive and agonizing that you aren&amp;rsquo;t keeping them alive perfectly enough to keep up with their peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final word is just as bad. &amp;ldquo;Balance&amp;rdquo; carries a lot of baggage. It implies that these two extremes must be actively managed, which makes sense until you start thinking about &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; is supposed to be doing that management. In nearly every usage of the phrase that I have seen, the responsibility to balance these two goals is presented as belonging to the individual only, and not to any employer or to society. At best the employer is presented as an enabler of &amp;ldquo;work-life balance,&amp;rdquo; not as its champion. Discussions around achieving &amp;ldquo;work-life balance&amp;rdquo; typically involve things like having flexible hours or working from home. Here&amp;rsquo;s the thing: you can&amp;rsquo;t achieve balance without changing the load. If many people in your industry are having problems with work-life balance, it is &lt;em&gt;not a flexibility problem,&lt;/em&gt; it is a work load problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;word-choice-matters&#34;&gt;Word Choice Matters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, if this were just an issue of poor word choice, the curmudgeon in me would complain, but I would just move on. But something more is going on here. The phrase &amp;ldquo;work-life balance&amp;rdquo; places these two ideas at opposite ends of a dialectic tension, which serves to draw hard lines around work in ways that we often take for granted because they are common in modernized economies. The truth is that these hard lines are largely an exception from the perspective of human history. The homestead was the site of a majority of work for most of recorded human existence. Even when work didn&amp;rsquo;t occur in the family residence, the family often spent time at the place of work. The separation of work and the rest of our lives is both artificial and recent. It is also, I think, harmful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
