<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Students’ perspectives on different teaching methods: Comparing innovative and traditional courses in a technology program</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/publication/debs-etal-2019-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/publication/debs-etal-2019-students/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSCA 2018, Nashville</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/ssca-2018-nashville/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/ssca-2018-nashville/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Attending regional conferences is one of the most exciting parts of my job. I always leave with so much inspiration from the work of the many amazing scholars across the country. This year, the Southern States Communication Association conference was held in Nashville from April 5th through April 8th, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even have to leave the state!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things about the SSCA conferences is its relaxed atmosphere and the opportunity to engage with so many welcoming people. Below is a summary of my professional activities at the conference, as well as links to all files used in the presentations I gave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tennessee-promise-panel&#34;&gt;Tennessee Promise Panel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;100%&#34; src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/conference/IMG_20180405_134501.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photograph of the members of the panel&#34; title=&#34;Brad Bailey, Jennifer James, Karen Johnson, Katelyn Brooks, Leonard Assante, and Scott Christen&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I presented as part of a panel of scholars discussing the impact of Tennessee Promise, a program designed to create &amp;ldquo;free community college&amp;rdquo; for students in Tennessee. We had the opportunity to discuss both the intended and unintended consequences of the program at a variety of institutions, including community colleges, 4-year public institutions, and 4-year private institutions. We were especially lucky to be placed in two back-to-back slots in the program for this discussion, which was lively and interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was honored to participate as the only representative of a private institution and the only representative of a small liberal-arts college. A special shout-out to Leonard Assante, Katelyn Brooks, Scott Christen, Jennifer James, Karen Johnson, Malcolm McAvoy, and Patrick Richey for their contributions to the panel, and to Brad Bailey for Chairing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gifts&#34;&gt;GIFTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a fantastic time presenting on a GIFTS panel! I presented a Great Idea For Teaching Students (GIFTS) titled &lt;em&gt;Slides Against Humanity&lt;/em&gt; in Session I. A special shout out to Doug Pruim for being the co-author on this presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Files from this presentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/conference/ssca18-gifts-example-visual-aid.pptx&#34;&gt;Visual aid (pptx)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/conference/ssca18-gifts-slides-against-humanity.docx&#34;&gt;Handout (docx)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/conference/Slides-Against-Humanity-Printable-cards.pdf&#34;&gt;Printable cards (pdf)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/conference/Slides-Against-Humanity-Printable-cards.pptx&#34;&gt;Editable cards (pptx)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-panel&#34;&gt;Feedback Panel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;100%&#34; src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/conference/IMG_20180407_155920.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photograph of the members of the panel&#34; title=&#34;Kurtis D. Miller, Jacob Metz, L&#39;Oreal Stephens, Karen Johnson, and Brad Bailey&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am so proud that I had the opportunity to work together with so many wonderful scholars to put together a panel on providing effective feedback at the 2018 Southern States Communication Association Conference. I organized a panel titled &lt;em&gt;Musings on Instructor Feedback: Improving the Process and Quality of Feedback&lt;/em&gt; which came out of a series of conversations at the 2017 Tennessee Communication Association conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My contribution to the panel was titled &lt;em&gt;Hashtag Feedback: Using Text Expansion to Streamline the Process of Providing Detailed Effective Feedback&lt;/em&gt;. A special shout out to Jacob Metz, L&amp;rsquo;Oreal Stephens, and Karen Johnson for their contributions to the panel, and to Brad Bailey for stepping in at the last minute to Chair in addition to preparing his own contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Files from this presentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/conference/ssca18-demo.pptx&#34;&gt;Visual aid (pptx)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/conference/ssca18-demo.ahk&#34;&gt;Demonstration script (ahk)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/conference/WinH-append-script.ahk&#34;&gt;Script for quickly adding new options (ahk)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;service&#34;&gt;Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was elected to be the secretary of the State Association Interest Group last year. This conference marked the end of my first year in that two-year position. This year I was appointed to serve on the Nominating Committee for the Instructional Development Division for the next conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Working the crowd:&#34; How political figures use introduction structures</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/publication/miller-2017-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/publication/miller-2017-working/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An AutoHotKey Script to Ease Switching Among Virtual Desktops in Windows</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/an-autohotkey-script-to-ease-switching-among-virtual-desktops-in-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/an-autohotkey-script-to-ease-switching-among-virtual-desktops-in-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update: as of 2019 I have switched to Linux and no longer use this script. I have no reason to believe it has stopped working, but I make no guarantees.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a big fan of &lt;a href=&#34;https://autohotkey.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AutoHotKey&lt;/a&gt;. It lets me make a lot of parts of computer interaction faster and easier for me. My most recent project was to make it faster and easier to switch between virtual desktops on my Windows 10 computer. Apple and Linux machines have employed virtual desktops for a long time, but Windows really lagged behind in this area. As a result, I was late to the party in adopting them. The easiest way to think about multiple desktops is to think about them as being literally multiple desktops that you are working on. If you have an office with a swivel chair, you know how easy it can be to swivel from the work you are doing on one desk to the reference documents you have laid out on another desk. Using virtual desktops works the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Windows hasn&amp;rsquo;t made creating or switching between multiple desktops very easy. First, you have to create all of the virtual desktops manually, which you can do by pressing the Windows key and the Tab key simultaneously. Then you need to click on the &amp;ldquo;New Desktop&amp;rdquo; link in the lower right corner of the screen. After that, you can switch between them by going to this selection screen, or with a keyboard shortcut by holding down the Windows key and the Control key while using the arrow keys to switch back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system is terrible. Using three keys at once is a pain, and the keys aren&amp;rsquo;t even on the same side of the keyboard, so I can&amp;rsquo;t switch one handed. Fortunately, I know how to fiddle with AutoHotKey to make things work better. I wrote this short script so I could hold down the blank key in the middle of my number pad (the &amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; key when NumLock is on) and switch back and forth by using the left and right arrows. This key didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything anyway, so it isn&amp;rsquo;t really a loss. This was my initial script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-autohotkey&#34;&gt;; switch to previous virtual desktop with NumLock Off
NumpadClear &amp;amp; NumpadLeft::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Left}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to next virtual desktop with NumLock off
NumpadClear &amp;amp; NumpadRight::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Right}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s right, it&amp;rsquo;s only two lines long, but it worked great! Soon, I realized that I use it a lot and toggling NumLock was annoying. In addition, if I added a couple lines to the script, the &amp;ldquo;5&amp;rdquo; key would always function normally anyway, unless I pressed another button while it was down. I added a few lines to the script and it was even better:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-autohotkey&#34;&gt;; switch to previous virtual desktop with NumLock On
Numpad5 &amp;amp; Numpad4::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Left}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to next virtual desktop with NumLock On
Numpad5 &amp;amp; Numpad6::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Right}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to previous virtual desktop with NumLock Off
NumpadClear &amp;amp; NumpadLeft::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Left}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to next virtual desktop with NumLock off
NumpadClear &amp;amp; NumpadRight::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Right}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
Numpad5::sendInput {Numpad5}
NumpadClear::sendevent {NumpadClear}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the script worked when NumLock was on and when it was off. It was perfect, except about 2 weeks later I was using my mouse and got annoyed with having to go back and forth between the keyboard and the mouse, since my number pad is also on the right side of my laptop. Then it hit me, I could switch back and forth using the left and right clicks on the mouse wheel, which I have never used for scrolling anyway. So, I added a few more lines to the script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-autohotkey&#34;&gt;; use Numpad keys to Navigate multiple virtual desktops

; switch to previous virtual desktop with NumLock On
Numpad5 &amp;amp; Numpad4::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Left}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to next virtual desktop with NumLock On
Numpad5 &amp;amp; Numpad6::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Right}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to previous virtual desktop with NumLock Off
NumpadClear &amp;amp; NumpadLeft::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Left}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to next virtual desktop with NumLock off
NumpadClear &amp;amp; NumpadRight::sendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Right}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
Numpad5::sendInput {Numpad5}
NumpadClear::sendevent {NumpadClear}

; use mouse wheel scroll left &amp;amp; right to navigate virtual desktops

; switch to previous virtual desktop
WheelLeft::SendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Left}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
; switch to next virtual desktop
WheelRight::SendInput {LWin down}{LCtrl down}{Right}{LWin up}{LCtrl up}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s perfect. I can spin my virtual chair between as many virtual desktops as I like. Now I can keep my e-mail and calendar up on one desktop and check it in a moment, rather than keeping it buried in a tab in my minimized browser. Now I can write in my dissertation and quickly skip over to look through a reference or my Zotero library quickly. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End-of-Semester Lessons - 2015F</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/end-of-semester-lessons-2015f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/end-of-semester-lessons-2015f/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;At the end of every semester I find that there are several things that I want to file away as important lessons for the future. I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I&amp;rsquo;ll use a categorical breakdown in the future, but I have broken down my list this semester into general lessons, lessons about teaching, and lessons about writing. They are, for lack of any better scheme, in alphabetical order. Here is my list for this semester:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general&#34;&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be discouraged when you fall short of your expectations – accept any degree of improvement.&lt;/strong&gt; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you aren&amp;rsquo;t able to live up to your initial ambitious plans. As long as you are doing better, to any degree, then you are successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on setting up good systems, not just having goals.&lt;/strong&gt; Goals are fantastic and useful, but they can also become a myopic focus that causes you to miss other great opportunities. It is just as important to know when NOT to use goals as it is to know how to set good goals. Often, it is the system you set up to achieve the goal that is actually important.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;teaching&#34;&gt;Teaching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have projects build on one another.&lt;/strong&gt; I have used similar strategies in the past, but this semester really underlined for me how important and beneficial this can be for students, especially in classes like presentational speaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Detailed emails are a waste of time – put that information somewhere other people can see it.&lt;/strong&gt; The information that you would put into an email, while potentially accessible forever, is almost certainly destined for obscurity. If what you are saying requires a lot of detail, then you need to find a better place to put it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I work best when I write in big chunks, AND ALSO write a little bit every day.&lt;/strong&gt; I find that writing a very small amount on my active project (dissertation) every day complements the writing that I do on dedicated writing days. It keeps the paper fresh in my mind and makes the big days much more productive. It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t hurt that these small days add up over time to real progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Being determined can be an obstacle to success – give up and work on something else.&lt;/strong&gt; If I am having trouble writing on one section of my dissertation, the worst thing I can do is keep bashing my head against the wall trying to force it to work. It&amp;rsquo;s OK to not be ready to work on a section yet. Just pivot, pick a different part of the problem, and drive on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define an actual writing process and framework.&lt;/strong&gt; Some writers tend to be verbose, I tend not to say enough. I became much more productive when I set a word-count goal for my dissertation. Then I had to figure out how to budget those words into chapters. Within each chapter I have had to budget it into sections. Defining a structure and targets as a framework has made me much more productive, because it lets me know that, even if I feel like I am done, I&amp;rsquo;m not done yet. In addition, I now have defined stages of the writing process that I track for each section. Now I know that my paper sections will go from &amp;ldquo;To-Do&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;First Draft&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Revised Draft&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Final Draft.&amp;rdquo; I cannot stress enough how important these features have become to my writing process. They are especially important tools for me when working on other projects in collaboration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using C-SPAN Data</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/using-cspan-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/using-cspan-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back on a weekly schedule, and loving having a bit more consistency. The students at my university are on Fall Break for Columbus Day, but I am working through it. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I took my break on Friday. This is just the price I pay for taking my day off a little bit early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The C-SPAN conference was amazing during the last week. I met &lt;a href=&#34;https://faculty.bentley.edu/details.asp?uname=agarcia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angela Garcia&lt;/a&gt; there, which was really cool. We were both presenting Conversation Analytic work that involved detailed analysis of data from the Archives. Her work using the Clinton Grand Jury testimony was really interesting. I spoke with her about putting together a panel for a future conference (possibly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.natcom.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NCA&lt;/a&gt; 2016 in Philadelphia) which would be composed of similar work. There appeared to be a lot of enthusiasm for the work I was doing, and I got some really interesting feedback as well. It isn&amp;rsquo;t my main research focus, but it is what I call my &amp;ldquo;research affair.&amp;rdquo; At least if I am blowing off what I am &amp;ldquo;supposed&amp;rdquo; to be doing, I am blowing it off to engage in a different productive line of research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though that is interesting, this is job application week, so that is my main area of focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading back over an older book on how educational organizations resist change, and how to implement change in spite of this resistance (&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?isbn=0877782717&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reigeluth &amp;amp; Garfinkle, 1994&lt;/a&gt;). I highly recommend it. Even though it is written with K-12 education as the primary subject, it has a lot of relevance to post-secondary (and even graduate &amp;amp; post-graduate) education as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Job Market is Upon Us</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/the-job-market-is-upon-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/the-job-market-is-upon-us/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So these have started to feel more like a monthly roundup rather than a weekly one, but I&amp;rsquo;m honestly happy as long as I&amp;rsquo;m fighting the good fight. My students are settled in, fall is in the air, and the kids are thinking about Halloween now. The federal government even managed to get a budget through without shutting down, so I&amp;rsquo;m feeling pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am presenting my C-SPAN research at conference next week. It has been really interesting to see how everyday introduction sequence norms are modified by candidates and others while the candidate is working the crowd. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to a future line of research that looks specifically at transactional encounters with these focal persons, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to put that off until I am back ahead on the dissertation, so perhaps it will be an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.natcom.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NCA&lt;/a&gt; submission for next year. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://associationdatabase.com/aws/CSCA/pt/sp/Home_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Central States Communication Association&lt;/a&gt; deadline is Saturday, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be putting some finishing touches on a submission or two for their teaching-focused division. I also am moving forward on projects on values-centered education and student experiences on organizational exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real crunch over the next week or two is on the job front. There are a ton of really interesting job announcements that have deadlines during the first three weeks of October, so I am doing a lot of applying. Fingers crossed for success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading over a piece from the Journal of Business and Psychology (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/B:JOBU.0000028449.99127.f7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bordia, Hobman, Jones, Gollois, &amp;amp; Callan, 1993&lt;/a&gt;) which details the effects of different types of uncertainty on members of organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settled into a New Semester - 2015F</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/settled-into-a-new-semester-2015f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/settled-into-a-new-semester-2015f/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The month of August just flew by between preparation for and the beginning of the first semester. My students are getting ready to give their first presentation next week, and I am starting to get into the swing of a routine. I enjoyed labor day weekend, and managed to make some significant progress around settling into the new residence, so that has done a lot for my peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been making a lot of moves on several different research projects at once. It feels at once exciting and overwhelming. I am glad to be moving so many projects forward, but I also am aware that these projects will be a temptation that could distract me from my main focus on my dissertation project over the course of this academic year. I&amp;rsquo;m moving forward on grant-funded research that utilizes the C-SPAN archives, which is a fantastic resource. I am a huge fan of it&amp;rsquo;s persistent linking abilities that allow you to link not only to a program, but to a clipped out portion of that program. It is a fantastic opportunity for much of the Conversation Analytic (CA) focused work that I do. Not all of my work is CA focused but, for the work that is, being able to share links that point specifically to examples of each of the phenomena that I am detailing is a fantastic feature for research in that tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also continuing in my support of the Transdisciplinary Studies in Technology educational research program in Purdue&amp;rsquo;s Polytechnic program, which has involved a lot of NVIVO work over the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading over a piece from Communication Monographs (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03637759309376307&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kramer, 1993&lt;/a&gt;) which details uncertainty processes in organizations. I&amp;rsquo;ll be tracking down and locating a good article or chapter on managing uncertainty during times of organizational change for my next set of readings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Friday Roundup</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/adding-a-friday-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/adding-a-friday-roundup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t done as much work on my dissertation over the summer up until this point as I had hoped that I would, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad. I needed some time to decompress and it has been hard to focus on work when so many more important social changes are coursing through the country. It is hard to focus on the importance of my small corner of academia when so many innocent (or at least not sufficiently guilty) people are being literally shot in the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the face of justice so poorly dispensed throughout the United States and media coverage of these tragedies which is nearly as poor, I know that I do have to refocus on advancing my own career as the new semester approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-am-i-adding-a-friday-roundup&#34;&gt;Why am I adding a Friday Roundup?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working on the dissertation for awhile. I have been following a pretty good piece of advice that I got fairly early in the process. &amp;ldquo;If you want to be an academic, you will have to first be a writer.&amp;rdquo; This has lead me to do a lot of reading about what kinds of tips I can find for how to be a better writer. I have read many, but the one which is relevant to this post is that the best way to become good at something is to do it a lot—if you are worried that you are not a very good writer, then the best thing you can do for your writing is to do a lot more of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that vein, these posts are serving to help me keep track of what I am doing, where I have been focused over the last week, where I am currently planning on going over the next week, and so forth. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty enthusiastic about my chances of success, to be honest. I think they will help quite a bit. In order to keep them from taking my focus away from the projects that I am supposed to be focusing on, I am strictly limiting the time that I spend on them and, as a direct consequence, the amount of editing and proofreading that I do. In short, to whomever does read these roundup posts, please excuse the inevitable poor writing and grammatical/typing errors—these pieces are not intended to be polished final products, they are working documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading back over an article in Communication Theory (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-2885.1992.tb00031.x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Babrow, 1992&lt;/a&gt;) on Problematic Integration. The piece discusses the importance of communication (by which he seems to mean interpersonal communication) in the experience of integration difficulties. I am curious how perspectives on communication by other types of actors fits into the theory. This is something that I plan to look into over the next week as I try to position my piece in the larger framework of research in the fields of Communication and Education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classroom Audio</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/classroom-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/classroom-audio/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The research team recorded an entire week&amp;rsquo;s worth of class meetings of three courses at four times during the course of the semester. These class meetings were recorded in video from four different angles. This resulted in a very large amount of data (approximately 200 hours of raw video) requiring about 1 Terabyte (1,000 Gigabytes) of storage space. The audio portion of the video was also rendered out and compressed into MP3 format files for ease of use and analysis when research questions can be answered without video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cleaning-classroom-audio&#34;&gt;Cleaning Classroom Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting MP3 files were much easier to process and store, but audio quality, which was lacking in the original raw video, still needed to be improved. In order to make the recording process unobtrusive, the cameras and microphones were installed at the ceiling in a large classroom. As a result, classroom audio recordings included a large amount of mid-frequency noise from building electrical and mechanical systems. This noise made it difficult to discern what individuals were saying on the recording.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to improve the quality of the classroom audio, I first equalized audio to remove reduce the volume of sounds at frequencies above and below those typical of speech. Frequencies below 1,000 Hz and above 7,000 Hz were reduced by 20 dB. Frequencies between 1,000 Hz and 7,000 Hz were reduced according to a generally bell-shaped curve centered near 2,800 Hz. Once audio had been equalized to focus on speech, the next priority was to reduce hissing, humming, and other constant noises which helped to mask speech. I used a noise removal tool integrated into the &lt;a href=&#34;web.audacityteam.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Audacity&lt;/a&gt; software package (v. 2.0.6). After selecting a noise profile for each track, I reduced noise by 48 dB on each recording (with a sensitivity of -1.00 dB and attack/decay of 0.20 seconds, utilizing a frequency smoothing window of 250 Hz). Finally, I converted each recording from a stereo recording to a mono recording and combined the recording for each camera – four total – into a single file, synchronized and balanced the audio sources, and exported the audio into a cleaned MP3 format audio file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This effort resulted in a noticeable increase in intelligibility and reduction in recording artifacts, especially loud, high- and low-frequency pops and bangs which had limited the listening volume of the recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selecting-classroom-audio&#34;&gt;Selecting Classroom Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classroom audio used for this dissertation come from the first week of classes because this is the time period where the highest amount of socialization of new organizational members (the students) typically occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- References --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
