<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dissertation on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/dissertation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dissertation on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/dissertation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using C-SPAN Data</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/using-cspan-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/using-cspan-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m back on a weekly schedule, and loving having a bit more consistency. The students at my university are on Fall Break for Columbus Day, but I am working through it. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I took my break on Friday. This is just the price I pay for taking my day off a little bit early.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The C-SPAN conference was amazing during the last week. I met &lt;a href=&#34;https://faculty.bentley.edu/details.asp?uname=agarcia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angela Garcia&lt;/a&gt; there, which was really cool. We were both presenting Conversation Analytic work that involved detailed analysis of data from the Archives. Her work using the Clinton Grand Jury testimony was really interesting. I spoke with her about putting together a panel for a future conference (possibly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.natcom.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NCA&lt;/a&gt; 2016 in Philadelphia) which would be composed of similar work. There appeared to be a lot of enthusiasm for the work I was doing, and I got some really interesting feedback as well. It isn&amp;rsquo;t my main research focus, but it is what I call my &amp;ldquo;research affair.&amp;rdquo; At least if I am blowing off what I am &amp;ldquo;supposed&amp;rdquo; to be doing, I am blowing it off to engage in a different productive line of research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though that is interesting, this is job application week, so that is my main area of focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading back over an older book on how educational organizations resist change, and how to implement change in spite of this resistance (&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?isbn=0877782717&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Reigeluth &amp;amp; Garfinkle, 1994&lt;/a&gt;). I highly recommend it. Even though it is written with K-12 education as the primary subject, it has a lot of relevance to post-secondary (and even graduate &amp;amp; post-graduate) education as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Job Market is Upon Us</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/the-job-market-is-upon-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/the-job-market-is-upon-us/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So these have started to feel more like a monthly roundup rather than a weekly one, but I&amp;rsquo;m honestly happy as long as I&amp;rsquo;m fighting the good fight. My students are settled in, fall is in the air, and the kids are thinking about Halloween now. The federal government even managed to get a budget through without shutting down, so I&amp;rsquo;m feeling pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am presenting my C-SPAN research at conference next week. It has been really interesting to see how everyday introduction sequence norms are modified by candidates and others while the candidate is working the crowd. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to a future line of research that looks specifically at transactional encounters with these focal persons, but I&amp;rsquo;ll have to put that off until I am back ahead on the dissertation, so perhaps it will be an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.natcom.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;NCA&lt;/a&gt; submission for next year. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://associationdatabase.com/aws/CSCA/pt/sp/Home_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Central States Communication Association&lt;/a&gt; deadline is Saturday, so I&amp;rsquo;ll be putting some finishing touches on a submission or two for their teaching-focused division. I also am moving forward on projects on values-centered education and student experiences on organizational exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the real crunch over the next week or two is on the job front. There are a ton of really interesting job announcements that have deadlines during the first three weeks of October, so I am doing a lot of applying. Fingers crossed for success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading over a piece from the Journal of Business and Psychology (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1023/B:JOBU.0000028449.99127.f7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bordia, Hobman, Jones, Gollois, &amp;amp; Callan, 1993&lt;/a&gt;) which details the effects of different types of uncertainty on members of organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Settled into a New Semester - 2015F</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/settled-into-a-new-semester-2015f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/settled-into-a-new-semester-2015f/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The month of August just flew by between preparation for and the beginning of the first semester. My students are getting ready to give their first presentation next week, and I am starting to get into the swing of a routine. I enjoyed labor day weekend, and managed to make some significant progress around settling into the new residence, so that has done a lot for my peace of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been making a lot of moves on several different research projects at once. It feels at once exciting and overwhelming. I am glad to be moving so many projects forward, but I also am aware that these projects will be a temptation that could distract me from my main focus on my dissertation project over the course of this academic year. I&amp;rsquo;m moving forward on grant-funded research that utilizes the C-SPAN archives, which is a fantastic resource. I am a huge fan of it&amp;rsquo;s persistent linking abilities that allow you to link not only to a program, but to a clipped out portion of that program. It is a fantastic opportunity for much of the Conversation Analytic (CA) focused work that I do. Not all of my work is CA focused but, for the work that is, being able to share links that point specifically to examples of each of the phenomena that I am detailing is a fantastic feature for research in that tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also continuing in my support of the Transdisciplinary Studies in Technology educational research program in Purdue&amp;rsquo;s Polytechnic program, which has involved a lot of NVIVO work over the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading over a piece from Communication Monographs (&lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/03637759309376307&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kramer, 1993&lt;/a&gt;) which details uncertainty processes in organizations. I&amp;rsquo;ll be tracking down and locating a good article or chapter on managing uncertainty during times of organizational change for my next set of readings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding a Friday Roundup</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/adding-a-friday-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/adding-a-friday-roundup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t done as much work on my dissertation over the summer up until this point as I had hoped that I would, and I&amp;rsquo;m glad. I needed some time to decompress and it has been hard to focus on work when so many more important social changes are coursing through the country. It is hard to focus on the importance of my small corner of academia when so many innocent (or at least not sufficiently guilty) people are being literally shot in the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even in the face of justice so poorly dispensed throughout the United States and media coverage of these tragedies which is nearly as poor, I know that I do have to refocus on advancing my own career as the new semester approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-am-i-adding-a-friday-roundup&#34;&gt;Why am I adding a Friday Roundup?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working on the dissertation for awhile. I have been following a pretty good piece of advice that I got fairly early in the process. &amp;ldquo;If you want to be an academic, you will have to first be a writer.&amp;rdquo; This has lead me to do a lot of reading about what kinds of tips I can find for how to be a better writer. I have read many, but the one which is relevant to this post is that the best way to become good at something is to do it a lot—if you are worried that you are not a very good writer, then the best thing you can do for your writing is to do a lot more of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that vein, these posts are serving to help me keep track of what I am doing, where I have been focused over the last week, where I am currently planning on going over the next week, and so forth. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty enthusiastic about my chances of success, to be honest. I think they will help quite a bit. In order to keep them from taking my focus away from the projects that I am supposed to be focusing on, I am strictly limiting the time that I spend on them and, as a direct consequence, the amount of editing and proofreading that I do. In short, to whomever does read these roundup posts, please excuse the inevitable poor writing and grammatical/typing errors—these pieces are not intended to be polished final products, they are working documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-focus-this-week&#34;&gt;Reading Focus this Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I have been reading back over an article in Communication Theory (&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468-2885.1992.tb00031.x&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Babrow, 1992&lt;/a&gt;) on Problematic Integration. The piece discusses the importance of communication (by which he seems to mean interpersonal communication) in the experience of integration difficulties. I am curious how perspectives on communication by other types of actors fits into the theory. This is something that I plan to look into over the next week as I try to position my piece in the larger framework of research in the fields of Communication and Education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classroom Audio</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/classroom-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/classroom-audio/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The research team recorded an entire week&amp;rsquo;s worth of class meetings of three courses at four times during the course of the semester. These class meetings were recorded in video from four different angles. This resulted in a very large amount of data (approximately 200 hours of raw video) requiring about 1 Terabyte (1,000 Gigabytes) of storage space. The audio portion of the video was also rendered out and compressed into MP3 format files for ease of use and analysis when research questions can be answered without video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cleaning-classroom-audio&#34;&gt;Cleaning Classroom Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting MP3 files were much easier to process and store, but audio quality, which was lacking in the original raw video, still needed to be improved. In order to make the recording process unobtrusive, the cameras and microphones were installed at the ceiling in a large classroom. As a result, classroom audio recordings included a large amount of mid-frequency noise from building electrical and mechanical systems. This noise made it difficult to discern what individuals were saying on the recording.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to improve the quality of the classroom audio, I first equalized audio to remove reduce the volume of sounds at frequencies above and below those typical of speech. Frequencies below 1,000 Hz and above 7,000 Hz were reduced by 20 dB. Frequencies between 1,000 Hz and 7,000 Hz were reduced according to a generally bell-shaped curve centered near 2,800 Hz. Once audio had been equalized to focus on speech, the next priority was to reduce hissing, humming, and other constant noises which helped to mask speech. I used a noise removal tool integrated into the &lt;a href=&#34;web.audacityteam.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Audacity&lt;/a&gt; software package (v. 2.0.6). After selecting a noise profile for each track, I reduced noise by 48 dB on each recording (with a sensitivity of -1.00 dB and attack/decay of 0.20 seconds, utilizing a frequency smoothing window of 250 Hz). Finally, I converted each recording from a stereo recording to a mono recording and combined the recording for each camera – four total – into a single file, synchronized and balanced the audio sources, and exported the audio into a cleaned MP3 format audio file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This effort resulted in a noticeable increase in intelligibility and reduction in recording artifacts, especially loud, high- and low-frequency pops and bangs which had limited the listening volume of the recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;selecting-classroom-audio&#34;&gt;Selecting Classroom Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classroom audio used for this dissertation come from the first week of classes because this is the time period where the highest amount of socialization of new organizational members (the students) typically occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- References --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why this Website?</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/why-this-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/why-this-website/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My adviser tells me that I am a &amp;ldquo;systems thinker.&amp;rdquo; She isn&amp;rsquo;t the first one to notice this – I know that she is right. I am constantly trying to optimize and improve the systems I use in my daily life. I notice when things aren&amp;rsquo;t working, and I &lt;strike&gt;obsess over&lt;/strike&gt; often think about ways to improve those processes. In fact, this can be quite a bit of a burden, because it means that I am constantly exposed to one of my greatest temptations to procrastination, and it quickly becomes self-reinforcing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I notice something about my workflow that isn&amp;rsquo;t working as well as it could.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I research, brainstorm and test ways to improve my workflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I notice that I&amp;rsquo;m not being very productive (because I&amp;rsquo;m not working).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repeat from step 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way I have found to counter this process is to find ways to accomplish multiple objectives at once, preferably by building on what I am already doing. This website is a part of that process. I have been having trouble working on my dissertation for quite some time now. I know that I need to be making progress, but it just isn&amp;rsquo;t working out for me. As a communication professional, I believe that I need a strong understanding of programming, web design and web development in general. I also need to know about writing for the Internet, because the Internet has become the primary place of consuming the written word. Finally, it is important to me to maintain my own online presence. I am envisioning that this website will help me to accomplish all of these goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-on-the-dissertation&#34;&gt;Working on the Dissertation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is my intention to post regularly about my progress on my dissertation. I don&amp;rsquo;t yet fully know what this will look like, but I do plan write posts about topics within the dissertation. This mimics the way that some classes require small, frequent assignments that can eventually yield much of the raw material in a final project. I may also post short descriptions, summaries, or reactions to pieces that I read. A lot of this is still up in the air, but what is important to me is that I derive benefit toward the dissertation and toward my eventual employment from working on the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;programming-web-design-and-web-development&#34;&gt;Programming, Web Design and Web Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Communication professional, and as a knowledge worker generally, I believe it is important to understand how the Internet works. I spend a significant amount of time working with a computer, which is one of the most powerful tools that humans have ever invented. It seems like if I don&amp;rsquo;t learn how to use it effectively, I will have squandered an opportunity to be fantastic at what I do. I already do much more of these things than the average graduate student does, but I believe the payoff is worth the effort. These tools are powerful, and they are changing the world. It is, in my opinion, worth the time spent to learn how to use them well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-for-the-internet&#34;&gt;Writing for the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing for an online audience is hard. I no longer know what students are taught in High School – it has been too long since I was there – but I have not been impressed by my students&amp;rsquo; writing skills. It seems that there is an over-emphasis on one particular genre of writing, which I find troubling. The majority of students who leave high school and college are not likely to engage in very much of the type of writing that they have been taught to produce in high school and college. This is a shame. Students are not generally taught to use non-verbal elements of writing, such as layout, text styles, images, and other things which help engage readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;maintaining-an-online-presence&#34;&gt;Maintaining an Online Presence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As knowledge workers, it is becoming increasingly important for academics to have an online presence. If I want to engage people outside the &amp;ldquo;Ivory Tower&amp;rdquo; of academia, then I will need to be accessible. Maintaining an online presence allows me to engage with others and to be find-able. As I continue in the job market, I am hopeful that it may also help me to find the type of job that I want.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
