<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>advice for undergrads on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/advice-for-undergrads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in advice for undergrads on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/advice-for-undergrads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Professional Emails</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/writing-professional-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/writing-professional-emails/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Engaging in professional communication with your professor is a good habit and it helps ensure that they have a good impression of you. Many students have difficulty using email effectively. If you are having trouble figuring out how to put together an email to your professor, you can&amp;rsquo;t go wrong with the template below. Whether you are in my class or any other class at the college, this template should work well. I have also included an example email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;addressing-and-header-information&#34;&gt;Addressing and Header Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;From:&lt;/dt&gt; &lt;dd&gt;Your official school email address.&lt;/dd&gt; 
  &lt;dt&gt;To:&lt;/dt&gt; &lt;dd&gt;Your professor&#39;s email address, as listed in the syllabus.&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Cc:&lt;/dt&gt; &lt;dd&gt;&#34;Carbon Copy&#34; - list anyone else you want to see your email, such as an advisor or coach. A good &#34;rule of thumb&#34; is to Cc anyone you mention in the email.&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Bcc:&lt;/dt&gt; &lt;dd&gt;&#34;Blind Carbon Copy&#34; – like Cc, but without letting the person you are sending the email to know that you have included other people. A good &#34;rule of thumb&#34; is NOT to use Bcc in most situations. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; Some email systems do not keep Bcc blind, letting the person in the &#34;To&#34; field see all recipients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Subject:&lt;/dt&gt; &lt;dd&gt;Start with your class and section. Then write the topic from &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; perspective. &#34;Class&#34; makes a terrible subject, because your professor teaches many classes and nearly all student emails are about one of those classes in some way.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;email-template&#34;&gt;Email Template&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replace the information in brackets below as appropriate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject: [class number and section]: [your issue]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear [Title, use &amp;ldquo;Professor&amp;rdquo; to be safe if you do not know] [Last Name],&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in your [time] [class name] class on [days class meets]. I have checked the [syllabus/assignment instructions/rubric/textbook/class resources] for an answer, but it does not adequately answer my question. I need some additional help with [your issue].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Second paragraph explaining your question. Describe where you looked for answers, what you found, and how that information is not enough for you to have a clear answer to your question. You may also include other relevant  aspects of your situation.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[OPTIONAL third paragraph where you propose answers or next steps.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Your First and Last Name]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-email&#34;&gt;Example Email&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From: examplestudent@tcstudents.tusculum.edu&lt;br&gt;
To: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:kdmiller@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kdmiller@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Cc:&lt;br&gt;
Bcc:&lt;br&gt;
Subject: SPCH 101-100: Hospitalization during late work window&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Dr. Miller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in your 9 am Public Speaking class on Monday/Thursday. I have checked the syllabus for an answer, but it does not adequately answer my question. I need some additional help with answering questions about hospitalization during the window for late work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I checked in the syllabus, it said that I could turn in a late presentation for partial credit as long as it was within 7 days of the original due date, but the syllabus does not address what happens if an injury or illness prevents a student from turning late work in during this 7-day window. I planned to turn in the presentation I missed during this late-work window, but I was injured at a game and had to stay in the hospital overnight. This hospital stay caused me to miss getting my late work in before the end of the late-work window. I have already completed and turned in the assignment, and I have attached a note from the hospital to this email to show that I was admitted and stayed overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that I cannot receive full credit for the assignment because I did not complete it prior to the  deadline but, considering these circumstances, can you accept my presentation and grade it as late work for partial credit even though I have submitted it after the 7-day window for late work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example Student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainstorming Topics for Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/brainstorming-topics-for-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/brainstorming-topics-for-presentations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The larger the set of topics you consider, the stronger the strongest topic will tend to be. You need to consider a large number of topics for your presentation. I generally recommend that my students consider &lt;strong&gt;around 100 topics&lt;/strong&gt; for each presentation they give in my classes. Coming up with 100 topics might seem difficult at first, but going in with a plan makes it much easier. Here are some tips to help you come up with that initial list of 100 topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write your topic ideas as a full-sentence claim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break brainstorming up into manageable chunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask friends, family, classmates, tutors, and others for help&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down every idea no matter how bad it is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use ideas you have already written down as fuel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;write-your-topic-ideas-as-a-full-sentence-claim&#34;&gt;Write your topic ideas as a full-sentence claim&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full-sentence claim is a complete sentence which says something that can be supported with evidence. Compare the difference between &amp;ldquo;King Kamehameha&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;King Kamehameha united the Hawaiian islands.&amp;rdquo; Coming up with a full-sentence claim will help you realize that there are actually several interesting topics within that broad category. It is much easier to brainstorm and compare specific topics than broad categories that only summarizes your topic area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;break-it-up-into-manageable-chunks&#34;&gt;Break it up into manageable chunks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it is possible to come up with 100 good ideas in one sitting, but coming up with ideas starts to get pretty hard after awhile. It is a lot easier if you plan on coming up with a smaller number of ideas in several sessions. Writing down just 15 ideas at each meal for 2 days gets you almost the whole way to 100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ask-friends-family-classmates-tutors-and-others-for-help&#34;&gt;Ask friends, family, classmates, tutors, and others for help&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brainstorming is easier in groups because you can be inspired by ideas that other people have. Asking for help with ideas for a topic is a great strategy. If the people that you are speaking with are similar to your target audience, it can also help you consider what topics your audience might find interesting. Plus, it gives you an excuse to call and ask your mom for her ideas, and moms love feeling like they helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;write-down-every-idea-no-matter-how-bad-it-is&#34;&gt;Write down every idea no matter how bad it is&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey! You thought of it (or someone helping you did), so give credit where credit is due! (Plus, are you really going to be the person that didn&amp;rsquo;t write down that idea your mom gave you?) &lt;strong&gt;Remember, evaluating the topics you write down comes later.&lt;/strong&gt; If your goal in brainstorming is to come up with 100 ideas to evaluate later, then in addition to 1 good idea you also need to find 99 bad ones. Brainstorming is easy if you aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to write down a bunch of terrible ideas. You are going to throw out most of your ideas at the end of this process anyway. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry! Even if you think an idea is terrible now, that terrible idea may prove useful later when you are having trouble coming up with anything at all and you will be glad you wrote it down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-ideas-you-have-already-written-down-as-fuel&#34;&gt;Use ideas you have already written down as fuel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no requirement for every idea you write down to be totally original. One way to help kick your brain into gear is to build on some of the other things that you have written down. A particularly useful mnemonic to help you figure out how to do this is SCAMPER&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:eberle-1996-scamper&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:eberle-1996-scamper&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. SCAMPER is a general purpose technique to improve brainstorming. The letters in SCAMPER stand for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Substitute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adapt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modify&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put to another use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reverse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:eberle-1996-scamper&#34;&gt;Eberle, B. (1996). &lt;em&gt;Scamper: Creative games and activities for imagination development.&lt;/em&gt; Waco, TX: Prufrock Press.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:eberle-1996-scamper&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students, Stop Telling me you Won&#39;t be in Class</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/students-stop-telling-me-you-wont-be-in-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/students-stop-telling-me-you-wont-be-in-class/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Every semester I get emails from students that bother me. Every teacher has different preferences. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect students to have mine memorized. Even so, I still find some especially annoying. The one that has been bothering me this week is the &amp;ldquo;hey, I won&amp;rsquo;t be in class, just so you know&amp;rdquo; email. I get it, I just don&amp;rsquo;t care—unless you make it &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; problem too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-get-it&#34;&gt;I Get It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was an undergraduate student too. I remember, and I understand. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect my class to always be your top priority, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me if it isn&amp;rsquo;t. Most traditional college students are new to adulthood, and I remember being new to adulthood myself. Being an adult almost always means juggling a variety of responsibilities and having to pick which ones are the most important at any given time. Sometimes you will have to prioritize your other classes. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to me what your reason is. If it is important enough to you to miss class, then it is important to &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, and that is what matters. It isn&amp;rsquo;t my place to judge your reasons for not being in class. I get it, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-don-t-care&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong—I care about you as a person. The thing is, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect me one way or another if you are in class. I don&amp;rsquo;t plan my classes around your presence, and I don&amp;rsquo;t wait to start class until you get there. I do the same thing whether you are there or not, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter to me if you will be in class. Heck, as a faceblind person, I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even notice that you weren&amp;rsquo;t there except for in classes where I take attendance (and even then I still struggle to connect your name with who you actually are anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;except-when-you-make-it-my-problem-too&#34;&gt;Except When You Make it &lt;em&gt;My&lt;/em&gt; Problem Too&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does bother me is when you want to prioritize for free. When you trade off one priority for another, there is always a cost. I just want you to handle it like an adult. You have plenty of classmates to get information from about the class that you missed, so don&amp;rsquo;t ask me what you missed. Course policies for attendance, missed deadlines, and missing coursework were all detailed in the course documents you have had access to since the beginning of the semester. Be an adult and accept the outcomes of your actions—they should not be a surprise to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are certain times when basic human compassion means you &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be exempted from the costs of missing a class. Fortunately, the vast majority of these instances are already covered under university policies for things like grief, illness, military service, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
