<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Public Speaking on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Public Speaking on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SPCH 101, Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SPCH 101: Public Speaking:&lt;/strong&gt; Speaking clearly and comfortably in
public is an essential skill set. This course prepares students for
a variety of professional situations in which formal presentations are
expected. Topics will include cultural conventions of speech, verbal and
nonverbal messaging, and techniques of oral presentation and persuasion.
Students will learn to research, outline, and deliver a variety of
speeches (e.g. demonstrative, informative, persuasive, special occasion,
etc.) of varying lengths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no prerequisites for this course, but students who need to
complete ENGL 100 are strongly encouraged to complete it prior to taking
this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The syllabus for this course is subject to change at any time. This
includes, but is not limited to, such elements as required assignments,
grading requirements/scales and the course calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructor-information&#34;&gt;Instructor Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Instructor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Office Hours&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kurtis D. Miller, PhD.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Library 126&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kurtisdmiller.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1:00 pm – 2:50 pm, Tuesdays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:kdmiller@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;kdmiller@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1:00 pm – 2:50 pm, Fridays&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;423-636-7300 Ext. 5783&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;also by appointment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Course Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will employ presentation aids which clearly and accurately
enhance their presentations. This outcome will be practiced by
preparing visual aids for presentations throughout the course. The
outcome will be assessed through performance on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support
Presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will complete a mediated presentation. The outcome will be
assessed through performance on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-education-student-learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;General Education Student Learning Outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing: Students will structure evidence to convincingly support their
arguments. This outcome will be practiced by preparing outlines for
presentations throughout the course. This outcome will be assessed
through performance on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking: Students will create messages appropriate to the
audience, purpose, and context. This outcome will be practiced in
presentations throughout the course. The outcome will be assessed
through performance in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking: Students will evaluate personal communication
strengths and weaknesses. This outcome will be practiced on the
Mid-term Exam. This outcome will be assessed on the Final Exam.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;required-materials&#34;&gt;Required Materials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The textbook for this course is &amp;ldquo;A Speaker&amp;rsquo;s Guidebook&amp;rdquo; (O&amp;rsquo;Hair, Stewart,
&amp;amp; Rubenstein). 5th or 6th edition are both acceptable. The textbook is
very affordable and there is also a copy on reserve in the library. In
addition to the textbook and standard classroom supplies, you will need
a flash drive, white 3x5 index cards, access to a video recording device
(such as a phone), and a YouTube account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-be-successful&#34;&gt;How to be Successful&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have taught hundreds of students. I have never seen a student do all
four of these things and fail:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn in all of your assignments by the deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliver every presentation by the deadline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to me if you are having trouble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to get at least a B:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do everything in the first list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes, including a short paragraph summary at the end of each class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review these notes when you get home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the notes again right before we start the next class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on your assignments before the day that they are due.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the directions on assignments and ask for help if you aren&amp;rsquo;t sure how to follow them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work ahead. Do not wait to start an assignment until the current assignment has been turned in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;em&gt;rarely&lt;/em&gt; seen a student do all seven of these things and not be
satisfied with their final grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;assignments-and-grading&#34;&gt;Assignments and Grading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your final grade will be determined by the total points received out of
1,000 points possible. The assignments receiving points are:
Participation, including attendance and classroom activities, 100
points; &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Presentation&lt;/a&gt;, 150
points; &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentation&lt;/a&gt;, 150 points; &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive
Presentation&lt;/a&gt;, 125 points; &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;, 75 points;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/peer-evaluations&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Peer Evaluations&lt;/a&gt;, 100 points; Midterm Exam, 100 points; Final Exam,
200 points. Students may earn up to 60 points of &lt;a href=&#34;#extra-credit&#34;&gt;Extra
Credit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-scale&#34;&gt;Grading Scale&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;Total Points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Grade&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Quality Points&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:tu-academic-policies&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:tu-academic-policies&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;930+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4.0 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 93% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;900+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;A-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3.7 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 90% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;880+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;B+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3.5 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 88% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;830+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3.0 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 83% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;800+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;B-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2.7 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 80% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;780+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;C+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2.5 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 78% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;730+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2.0 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 73% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;700+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;C-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1.7 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 70% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;680+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;D+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1.5 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 68% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;630+&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;D&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1.0 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 63% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;right&#34;&gt;less than 630&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;0.0 per semester hour  &lt;!-- 00% --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extra-credit&#34;&gt;Extra Credit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students may earn up to 60 points by participating in debate team practice
sessions, 20 points for each session. Additional extra credit
opportunities may also be announced as they become available. Extra Credit
may not be turned in after the last class meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-policies&#34;&gt;Course Policies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;appropriate-topic-policy&#34;&gt;Appropriate Topic Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation topics should be appropriate for a classroom of college-aged
professionals. See the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/courses/public-speaking/assignment/presentation-topics/&#34;&gt;presentation topics&lt;/a&gt; resource for assastance
with picking a strong topic. Students should not present on duplicate
topics. Students can claim topics using the course management system. The
first student to post a topic will be allowed to present on it. Any other
presentation on that topic will be graded for half credit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;email-policy&#34;&gt;Email Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email is the primary and preferred method of communication for most
student issues. I check and respond to my email once daily, except
weekends and holidays. You should plan to check your official student
email account on a similar schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The privacy of student educational records is protected by the Family
Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). I will not respond to any
communication about a student which does not come from an official school
email address. I do not accept assignments by email. I do not reply to
emails asking questions which are already answered in course documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engaging in professional communication with your professors and the
university staff is important. Some students benefit from the below email
template, which comes from a post I wrote to help students with &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/writing-professional-emails/&#34;&gt;writing
professional emails&lt;/a&gt;. Whether you are in my class or any other class at
the university, this template should work well. Just replace the
information in brackets as needed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject: [class number and section]: [your issue]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear [Title Last Name  – if you can&amp;rsquo;t find out, use &amp;ldquo;Professor&amp;rdquo; to be
safe],&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am in your [time] [class name] class on [days class meets]. I have
checked the [syllabus/assignment instructions/rubric/textbook/class
resources] for an answer, but it does not adequately answer my question.
I need some additional help with [your issue].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Second paragraph explaining your question. Describe where you looked
for answers, what you found, and how that information is not enough for
you to have a clear answer to your question. You may also include other
relevant  aspects of your situation.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[OPTIONAL third paragraph where you propose answers or next steps.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Your First and Last Name]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-exam-policy&#34;&gt;Final Exam Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final exam is a required part of this course; students must take the
final in order to pass the course. Final exams are idministered only
during three days of Final Exam Week and may not be taken early for any
reason. Consult the syllabus and the Tusculum website to determine when
your exams will take place and do not make travel, family, or any other
plans that conflict with any of your final exams. If you see that there
will be an unavoidable conflict, drop this course before the Add/Drop
period concludes and sign up for a different section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grade-check-policy&#34;&gt;Grade Check Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prepare your grade check form with information from the course management
system (Moodle) prior to bringing it to me. Please remember that grade
check forms are not binding. Final grade estimates for classes in progress
are based on incomplete information. FERPA restrictions prevent me from
looking up your grade in front of other students. This means I must rely
on my memory of how students are doing in the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grade-disputes&#34;&gt;Grade Disputes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you believe that you have been graded unfairly, wait 24 hours after
receiving the grade and schedule a meeting to discuss it with me. I cannot
discuss your grades publically. Come to this meeting prepared to provide
evidence supporting the need for a grade change. Grades are considered
final one week after they are returned to you (or 2 days after the last
class meeting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;late-work-policy&#34;&gt;Late Work Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late work may be turned in up to 7 days after the deadline. Late work will
be graded &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;pass/fail for half credit without feedback.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Late work that
would normally receive a &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo; or higher will receive 50% of the maximum
points available. Late work that is not at least &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo; quality will receive
zero points. Late work is not accepted after 7 days. Class time will not
be provided for late presentations. Presentations may be turned in late by
following the instructions for &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/submitting-presentations-by-video&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;video submission&lt;/a&gt;. Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/submitting-presentations-by-video&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;video
submission&lt;/a&gt; link for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;alternate-deadlines&#34;&gt;Alternate Deadlines&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some rare cases an emergency may require you to miss class and turn in
work after the assigned due date. These situations are handled on
a case-by-case basis and, depending on the situation and documentation,
this work may be assigned an alternate deadline. Coursework assigned an
alternate deadline is graded for full credit, but will not receive
feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternate deadlines will not be assigned for absences that can be planned
for &amp;ndash; this includes school-sponsored events, such as athletics.
Presentations may always be turned in early using &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/submitting-presentations-by-video&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;video submission&lt;/a&gt;.
Follow the &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/submitting-presentations-by-video&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;video submission&lt;/a&gt; link for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;participation-policy&#34;&gt;Participation Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Particpation will be considered as part of the course grade. Students who
are not present and actively engaged in the course will not be awarded
participation points, regardless of the cause for their inibility to be
present and actively engaged. Students are expected to be present and on
time for all classroom activities and are held responsible for all
learning activity missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;technology&#34;&gt;Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will often use laptops/tablets/phones or other personal electronic
devices for class activities. Outside of these activities, all devices
should be stored out of sight with sound switched off. There is no
exception for activities such as checking the time, taking notes, or
accessing copies of readings for the class. Headphones should not be worn.
Please contact me if you require an exception to any course policy. Please
see the section on
&lt;a href=&#34;#academic-accommodations-and-students-with-disibilities&#34;&gt;Accommodations&lt;/a&gt;
for additional information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These policies are in place because students using cell phones during
class take less detailed notes, and score an average of 1.5 letter grades
lower on multiple choice tests.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:kuznekoff-titsworth-2013&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:kuznekoff-titsworth-2013&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Research
clearly shows that increases in student cell phone use during class are
associated with lower GPAs and lower test
performance.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Bjornsen-Archer-2015-StudentCellPhone&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Bjornsen-Archer-2015-StudentCellPhone&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Studies also show
that students remember information better when they hand-write their
notes&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Mueller-Oppenheimer-2014-PenMightier&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Mueller-Oppenheimer-2014-PenMightier&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and that using laptops in the
classroom has negative effects on the learning of those around
you.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Sana-etal-2013-LaptopMultitasking&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Sana-etal-2013-LaptopMultitasking&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-issues&#34;&gt;Technology Issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues with technology are not an excuse for late or missing work. Using
technology is a basic expectation of students at this level of study.
I strongly suggest that you do not wait until the last minute to complete
assignments in order to allow time to resolve any technological issues
that arise. If you need assistance with technology, contact &lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.tusculum.edu/is/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Information
Services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;university-policies&#34;&gt;University Policies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following policies apply to &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; courses at Tusculum University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;minimum-grade-for-a-course-to-count-toward-a-major-or-minor&#34;&gt;Minimum Grade for a Course to Count Toward a Major or Minor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grades below C- earned in the student’s major and minor will satisfy the
course prerequisites requirement; however, grades below C- cannot be
counted in the total number of hours required in the major and minor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tusculum-communication-policy&#34;&gt;Tusculum Communication Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All students are responsible for checking their personal Tusculum
University email account each day, as it is the university’s only official
communication tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plagiarism-and-academic-dishonesty-policy&#34;&gt;Plagiarism and Academic Dishonesty Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheating and plagiarism are violations of Ethics of Social
Responsibility &amp;ndash; one of the outcomes that has been identified as essential
to the Civic Arts. Plagiarism is a form of academic dishonesty. It
consists of knowingly presenting in writing or in speech the intellectual
or creative work of others as if it were one’s own. This includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failing to identify direct or word-for-word quotations by use of appropriate symbols and reference to the source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restating in your own words the work (ideas, conclusions, words) of another without reference to the source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presenting as your own the creative work (for instance, music or photographs) of another without proper acknowledgment. Besides plagiarism, other forms of academic dishonesty include the following:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitting the same work in two or more courses without significant modifications or expansion and without the approval of the instructors involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submitting purchased, borrowed, copied or specially commissioned work as if it were one’s own.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowingly permitting others to submit your work under their names.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copying the work of others during an examination or other academic exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowingly allowing others to copy your work during an examination or other academic exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using “cheat sheets” or any other unauthorized form of assistance during an exam, quiz or other academic exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manipulating or fabricating data to support erroneous conclusions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic-accommodations-and-students-with-disabilities&#34;&gt;Academic Accommodations and Students with Disabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tusculum University makes available to qualified students with
disabilities those reasonable accommodations or services as are necessary
to provide such students with unrestricted access to the learning
environment and the opportunity to demonstrate academic achievement.  In
order to procure services or classroom accommodations, the qualified
student is responsible for self-identifying and directing all requests or
accommodations or services to the Academic Resource Center counselors.
Contact information:  Counseling and ADA Services, 423-636-7300, ext.
5402;
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:counselingandadaservices@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;counselingandadaservices@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt;;
Room 233, Garland Library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tutoring&#34;&gt;Tutoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free tutoring services are provided by Tusculum University. The campus
Tutoring Center is located in the Garland Library on the Greeneville
campus.  Tutoring is available in English and Mathematics, including
Statistics, in the Tutoring Center, Rooms 317-318, 9:00 AM – 5:00 PM,
Monday through Friday. For all other subjects, sign in at the Garland
Library Circulation Desk (Main Floor/2nd floor),7:00 PM – 9 PM, Sunday
through Thursday.  Tutoring is available during the stated hours on
a walk-in basis, and you can also schedule an appointment by emailing
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tutoring@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tutoring@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt;.  In some
circumstances, written approval to meet in other public locations can be
obtained from the Tutor Coordinator.  Please note that the faculty
reserves the right to require students to attend tutoring sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;title-ix&#34;&gt;Title IX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tusculum University is committed to providing a safe learning environment
that is free of all forms of sex and gender-based discrimination and
harassment, including sexual assault, intimate partner violence, and
stalking.  If you or someone you know has experienced any form of sexual
misconduct, you are strongly encouraged (but not required) to contact the
Title IX Co-Coordinators at (423) 636-7318 or email either of them:
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jgresham@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;jgresham@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mcooney@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mcooney@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt;). Please note that all
Tusculum University faculty members are considered “responsible
employees,” meaning any situation involving sex or gender-based
discrimination shared with faculty must be reported to the Title IX
Co-Coordinators.  If you wish to speak with someone confidentially,
contact Dr. Michell Temple (Garland Library 233; tel. 423-636-7402;
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:counselingandadaservices@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;counselingandadaservices@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt;).
For more information regarding Title IX reporting options and links to
available resources, please visit
&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.tusculum.edu/titleix/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://web.tusculum.edu/titleix/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inclement-weather-policy&#34;&gt;Inclement Weather Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Tusculum University classes are cancelled due to inclement weather,
students will receive direction on how to complete scheduled and assigned
activities on the Moodle site.  In the case of inclement weather and the
University is not closed, students and faculty are to exercise good
judgment concerning personal safety related to traveling.  If the
University does not close and students miss class, they are responsible
for contacting the course instructor prior to the class. Tusculum
University will post information regarding closings or changes in the
schedule on the home page of the university website, as well as to the
Tusculum Facebook page and the Twitter feed. All students are encouraged
to sign up for the Pioneer Alert system by following the instructions at
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www3.tusculum.edu/pr/inclement-weather-policy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www3.tusculum.edu/pr/inclement-weather-policy/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;student-veterans&#34;&gt;Student Veterans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For information on support provided by Tusculum to veterans, contact Dale
Laney, Director of Veteran Services, 121 Garland Library, tel.
423-636-7371, or &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:dlaney@tusculum.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;dlaney@tusculum.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Assignment Links --&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:tu-academic-policies&#34;&gt;Tusculum University. (n.d.). &lt;em&gt;Academic Policies.&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved from: &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.tusculum.edu/academics/academic-policies/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://web.tusculum.edu/academics/academic-policies/&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:tu-academic-policies&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:kuznekoff-titsworth-2013&#34;&gt;Kuznekoff, J. H., &amp;amp; Titsworth, S. (2013). The Impact of Mobile Phone Usage on Student Learning. &lt;em&gt;Communication Education, 62&lt;/em&gt;(3), 233–252. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/03634523.2013.767917&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1080/03634523.2013.767917&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:kuznekoff-titsworth-2013&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Bjornsen-Archer-2015-StudentCellPhone&#34;&gt;Bjornsen, C. A., &amp;amp; Archer, K. J. (2015). Relations between college students’ cell phone use during class and grades. &lt;em&gt;Scholarship of Teaching and Learning in Psychology, 1&lt;/em&gt;(4), 326–336. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1037/stl0000045&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1037/stl0000045&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Bjornsen-Archer-2015-StudentCellPhone&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Mueller-Oppenheimer-2014-PenMightier&#34;&gt;Mueller, P. A., &amp;amp; Oppenheimer, D. M. (2014). The pen is mightier than the keyboard: Advantages of longhand over laptop note taking. &lt;em&gt;Psychological Science, 25&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1159–1168. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797614524581&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797614524581&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Mueller-Oppenheimer-2014-PenMightier&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Sana-etal-2013-LaptopMultitasking&#34;&gt;Sana, F., Weston, T., &amp;amp; Cepeda, N. J. (2013). Laptop multitasking hinders classroom learning for both users and nearby peers. &lt;em&gt;Computers &amp;amp; Education, 62&lt;/em&gt;, 24–31. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2012.10.003&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2012.10.003&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Sana-etal-2013-LaptopMultitasking&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPCH 101-100, Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/spch-101-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/spch-101-100/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;section-information&#34;&gt;Section Information&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M/Th, 12:30 - 1:45, Library 105&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;calendar&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;| #  | Date     | Topic                                                    | Resources                   | Due                                                | To prepare…                               |
|:-|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;|
|  1 | M,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt; | Course Overview                                          | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/course-overview/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/SPCH-101-100-FA19-KM.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Handout - Syllabus&#34;&gt;HO&lt;/a&gt;     | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  2 | R,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;22&lt;/sub&gt; | Choosing a Topic                                         | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/topic-selection/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  3 | M,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;26&lt;/sub&gt; | Introductions, Transitions, &amp;amp; Conclusions                | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/introductions-transitions-and-conclusions/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  4 | R,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;29&lt;/sub&gt; | Preparation Outlines                                     | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/preparation-outlines/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  - | M,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;02&lt;/sub&gt; | No Classes, Labor Day                                    | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  5 | R,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;05&lt;/sub&gt; | Organizing Informative Presentations                     | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-informative-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  6 | M,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt; | Supporting Evidence                                      | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/supporting-evidence/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  7 | R,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; | Outline Workshop                                         | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/outline-rubric.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Handout - Outline Grading Rubric&#34;&gt;HO&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  8 | M,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;16&lt;/sub&gt; | Visual Aid Design                                        | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-aid-design/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/visual-aid/example-visual-aid.pptx&#34; title=&#34;Visual Aid&#34;&gt;VA&lt;/a&gt;   | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  9 | R,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt; | Plagiarism &amp;amp; Intellectual Property                       | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/plagiarism-and-intellectual-property/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Outline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                   | Bring a completed outline for Mediated    |
| 10 | M,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;23&lt;/sub&gt; | Finding and Using Images                                 | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/finding-and-using-images/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 11 | R,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;26&lt;/sub&gt; | Visual Presentation of Data                              | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-presentation-of-data/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 12 | M,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;30&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Midterm Exam&lt;/strong&gt;                                         | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;Midterm Exam&lt;/strong&gt;                                   | Study                                     |
| 13 | R, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;03&lt;/sub&gt; | Mediated Presentations, Visual Aid Workshop              | [HO1][ho-grp], &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/presentation-rubric.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Handout - Presentation Rubric&#34;&gt;HO2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Graded PowerPoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;         | Bring a completed visual aid for Mediated |
| 14 | M, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;07&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                   | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;              | -                                         |
| 15 | R, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; | Crisis Response Presentations                            | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/crisis-response-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 16 | M, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt; | Verbal and Nonverbal Delivery                            | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/verbal-and-nonverbal-delivery/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 17 | R, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;17&lt;/sub&gt; | Organizing Persuasive Presentations, Visual Aid Workshop | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-persuasive-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Outline &amp;amp; Graded PowerPoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; | -                                         |
|  - | M, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;21&lt;/sub&gt; | No Classes, Fall Break                                   | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 18 | R, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;24&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                     | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                | -                                         |
| 19 | M, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                     | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                | -                                         |
| 20 | R, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;31&lt;/sub&gt; | Special Occasion Speeches                                | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/special-occasion-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 21 | M, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;04&lt;/sub&gt; | Presenting Beyond the Classroom                          | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Outline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | Interview a friend or family member       |
| 22 | R, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;07&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;          | -                                         |
| 23 | M, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;          | -                                         |
| 24 | R, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;14&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;          | -                                         |
| 25 | M, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt; | Competitive Debate                                       | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 26 | R, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;21&lt;/sub&gt; | Competitive Debate                                       | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 27 | M, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;25&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
|  - | R, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;28&lt;/sub&gt; | No Classes, Thanksgiving                                 | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 28 | M, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;02&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
| 29 | R, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;05&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
| 30 | M, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;09&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
| 31 | R, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Final Exam&lt;/strong&gt; at 2:00 pm                                | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;Final Exam&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | Study                                     |&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Assignment Links --&gt;

&lt;!-- handout links --&gt;

&lt;!-- lesson plan links --&gt;

&lt;!-- visual aid links--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPCH 101-101, Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/spch-101-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/spch-101-101/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;section-information&#34;&gt;Section Information&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fall 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tu/F 8:00 - 9:15, Library 105&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;calendar&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;| #  | Date     | Topic                                                    | Resources                   | Due                                                | To prepare…                               |
|:-|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;|
|  1 | T,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; | Course Overview                                          | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/course-overview/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/SPCH-101-101-FA19-KM.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Handout - Syllabus&#34;&gt;HO&lt;/a&gt;     | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  2 | F,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;23&lt;/sub&gt; | Choosing a Topic                                         | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/topic-selection/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  3 | T,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;27&lt;/sub&gt; | Introductions, Transitions, &amp;amp; Conclusions                | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/introductions-transitions-and-conclusions/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  4 | F,  &lt;sup&gt;8&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;30&lt;/sub&gt; | Preparation Outlines                                     | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/preparation-outlines/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  5 | T,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;03&lt;/sub&gt; | Organizing Informative Presentations                     | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-informative-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  6 | F,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;06&lt;/sub&gt; | Supporting Evidence                                      | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/supporting-evidence/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  7 | T,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; | Outline Workshop                                         | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/outline-rubric.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Handout - Outline Grading Rubric&#34;&gt;HO&lt;/a&gt;                 | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  8 | F,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt; | Visual Aid Design                                        | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-aid-design/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/visual-aid/example-visual-aid.pptx&#34; title=&#34;Visual Aid&#34;&gt;VA&lt;/a&gt;   | -                                                  | -                                         |
|  9 | T,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;17&lt;/sub&gt; | Plagiarism &amp;amp; Intellectual Property                       | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/plagiarism-and-intellectual-property/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Outline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                   | Bring a completed outline for Mediated    |
| 10 | F,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;20&lt;/sub&gt; | Finding and Using Images                                 | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/finding-and-using-images/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 11 | T,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;24&lt;/sub&gt; | Visual Presentation of Data                              | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-presentation-of-data/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 12 | F,  &lt;sup&gt;9&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;27&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Midterm Exam&lt;/strong&gt;                                         | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;Midterm Exam&lt;/strong&gt;                                   | Study                                     |
| 13 | T, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;01&lt;/sub&gt; | Mediated Presentations, Visual Aid Workshop              | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/graded-powerpoint-rubric.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Handout - Graded PowerPoint Rubric&#34;&gt;HO1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/presentation-rubric.pdf&#34; title=&#34;Handout - Presentation Rubric&#34;&gt;HO2&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Graded PowerPoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;         | Bring a completed visual aid for Mediated |
| 14 | F, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;04&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                   | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Mediated Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;              | -                                         |
| 15 | T, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;08&lt;/sub&gt; | Crisis Response Presentations                            | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/crisis-response-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 16 | F, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt; | Verbal and Nonverbal Delivery                            | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/verbal-and-nonverbal-delivery/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 17 | T, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt; | Organizing Persuasive Presentations, Visual Aid Workshop | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-persuasive-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Outline &amp;amp; Graded PowerPoint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; | -                                         |
| 18 | F, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                     | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| -  | T, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;22&lt;/sub&gt; | No Classes, Fall Break                                   | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                | -                                         |
| 19 | F, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;25&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                     | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Support Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                | -                                         |
| 20 | T, &lt;sup&gt;10&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;29&lt;/sub&gt; | Special Occasion Speeches                                | &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/special-occasion-presentations/&#34; title=&#34;Lesson Plan&#34;&gt;LP&lt;/a&gt;                | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 21 | F, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;01&lt;/sub&gt; | Presenting Beyond the Classroom                          | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Outline&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | Interview a friend or family member       |
| 22 | T, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;05&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;          | -                                         |
| 23 | F, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;08&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;          | -                                         |
| 24 | T, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;               | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Persuasive Presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;          | -                                         |
| 25 | F, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt; | Competitive Debate                                       | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 26 | T, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;19&lt;/sub&gt; | Competitive Debate                                       | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| 27 | F, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;22&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
| 28 | T, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;26&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | -                                                  | -                                         |
| -  | F, &lt;sup&gt;11&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;29&lt;/sub&gt; | No Classes, Thanksgiving                                 | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
| 29 | T, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;03&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
| 30 | F, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;06&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                       | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment&#34; title=&#34;Assignment description&#34;&gt;Debate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | -                                         |
| 31 | T, &lt;sup&gt;12&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;10&lt;/sub&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Final Exam&lt;/strong&gt; at 8:00 am                                | -                           | &lt;strong&gt;Final Exam&lt;/strong&gt;                                     | Study                                     |&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Assignment Links --&gt;

&lt;!-- handout links --&gt;

&lt;!-- lesson plan links --&gt;

&lt;!-- visual aid links--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mediated Presentation</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-assignment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; You will need to prepare a brief recorded presentation that can
be consumed anywhere in the world through using electronic media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; More and more presentations occur through electronic media. The
ability to record and distribute a presentation electronically has made it far
easier to reach a much greater number of people all over the world. This
presentation allows you to edit and re-record portions of your presentation,
and allows you to present without the pressure of a live audience, which is
useful in helping new presenters overcome presentation anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Length:&lt;/strong&gt; 7 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due:&lt;/strong&gt; See the calendar for your section for due dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detailed-description&#34;&gt;Detailed Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose a historically significant person in your major area of study. Provide
an informative presentation that informs your audience about the events which
make this person historically significant to your future field. If you have
more than one declared major, choose a person from one of your major areas. If
you do not have a major area, choose someone who has had a historically
significant impact on the field of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communication_studies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Communication
Studies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;Historically significant&amp;rdquo; means that their actions have caused
a significant change in that field.  Many people who are historically
significant do not end up being famous or very successful. While some people
that are very successful in a field cause significant changes, many very
successful people are not historically significant to any field. Likewise,
while some people who are famous cause significant changes in a field, many do
not. Finally, remember that a person may change a field without being in that
field themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should not choose someone who is currently active in their career.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must use a PowerPoint-style visual aid which uses the assertion-evidence
structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need to record the presentation and save it in a commonly-used video
format in order to upload video to YouTube. Like all presentations, your
mediated presentation should include an effective introduction, body, and
conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is graded out of 150 points. 25 points come from the
preparation outline, 25 points come from the graded PowerPoint, and 100
points come from the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-rubric&#34;&gt;Outline Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outline portion of this assignment is worth 25 points. (Yes, you get
a sneaky bonus point! Shh, it&amp;rsquo;s not a math class!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Voice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written as the presenter would speak to the audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in complete sentences, but not in a spoken style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline has occasional sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Complete and effective introduction, supported main points, and conclusion, all separated by effective transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction, supported main points, or conclusion are ineffective. All transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction or conclusion incomplete. Supported main points. Some transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sections or transitions are missing or main points are not supported.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline Principles&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline follows the principles of parallelism, coordination, subordination, and division.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks one of the outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks no more than two outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks multiple outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;In-text Citations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and mostly written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and are written using APA/MLA style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are not present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Reference Section&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly and in APA format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed, but have errors.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are not listed or are listed incorrectly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses a professional 12 point font, double spaced. Effective and consistent numbering and indentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one minor inconsistency in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one major inconsistency or two minor inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Multiple inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Evidence with citation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing is plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;graded-powerpoint-rubric&#34;&gt;Graded PowerPoint Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graded PowerPoint portion of this assignment is worth 25 points. (Yes,
you get a sneaky bonus point! Shh, it&amp;rsquo;s not a math class!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Supports the Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses a variety of types of visual evidence to support assertions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses visual evidence to support assertions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Majority of slides are text only.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No visual evidence included.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Professional&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The visual aid has a unified visual style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fonts, colors, and presentation of visual evidence are consistent on most slides.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fonts, colors, and presentation of visual evidence are inconsistent.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Contents of slides are inappropriate for professional use.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References and Citations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations and complete reference information for all evidence in the visual in APA format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations included for most evidence in the visual aid. Complete reference information included.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Majority of evidence is missing citation &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; reference information.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citation &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing throughout visual aid.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Accessible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that are accessible and appropriate for a general audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that hinder usability for some audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that hinder usability for average audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Significant problems with accessibility. Slides not useful for average audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Formatted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;All content slides use Assertion-Evidence structure.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;One error in Assertion-Evidence structure appears on one content slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;One error in Assertion-Evidence structure appears on multiple content slides.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Content slides have multiple errors of many kinds.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Evidence with citation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing is plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-rubric&#34;&gt;Presentation Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation portion of this assignment is worth 100 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;20 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;15 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;5 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Topic Fit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is compelling and interesting for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment or audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is inappropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is compelling and adds to the presentation. Complete and effective introduction, conclusion, and transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is clear. Complete introduction and conclusion. Transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of organization unclear. Portions of introduction or conclusion missing. One transition missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No organization clear to audience. Significant problems with introduction or conclusion. Transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points are effectively supported. Evidence cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points supported. Most evidence is cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis not supported by main points or support for main points missing. Citations for evidence are incomplete.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and/or main points missing. No citations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delivery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Verbally fluent and nonverbally engaging.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Minor issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would not distract a general audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Distracting issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would distract many audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Significant delivery issues that prevent even motivated audience members from understanding.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Time Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 30 seconds of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 1 minute of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 2 minutes of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation significantly short or had to be stopped.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some example outlines for mediated presentations given in this
class.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:student-permission&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:student-permission&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-outline-example-1.docx&#34;&gt;Example Mediated Outline
1&lt;/a&gt; is
a well-formatted outline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-mediated-outline-1.docx&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/course/mediated-outline-example-1.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Example Mediated Outline 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-outline-example-2.docx&#34;&gt;Example Mediated Outline
2&lt;/a&gt;
does a very good job with using oral citations throughout the
presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-mediated-outline-2.docx&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/course/mediated-outline-example-2.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Example Mediated Outline 2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/visual-aid/example-visual-aid.pptx&#34;&gt;example of a visual
aid&lt;/a&gt; that uses
the Assertion-Evidence structure for each of the three forms of evidence
which are commonly presented visually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/visual-aid/example-visual-aid.pptx&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/course/example-visual-aid.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Example Visual
Aid&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example mediated presentation that has been prepared using a narrated PowerPoint presentation.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/9oiPG1VIzR4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;acknowledgments&#34;&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special thanks to students in my 2017-18 Speech 101-11 class for their suggestions to improve this assignment, incorporated beginning in v3.00.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v3.03 | 2019-08-08 | Changes for Hugo compatibility, integrated and updated rubrics
  v3.02 | 2018-01-16 | moved presentation specific components to standalone assignment
  v3.01 | 2017-10-24 | Fixed link to graded PowerPoint assignment
  v3.00 | 2017-10-10 | Changed assignment to focus on major.
  v2.03 | 2017-10-03 | Added text for choosing a topic
  v2.02 | 2017-09-20 | Minor formatting fixes
  v2.01 | 2017-09-12 | Added link to preparation outline assignment and example outlines
  v2.00 | 2017-08-15 | Transitioned to star system.
  v1.02 |          - | Added example
  v1.01 |          - | spell check :-)
  v1.00 |          - | New assignment format, more restrictions, moved to first assignment
  v0.02 |          - | Formatting, wording, link for reflection paper
  v0.01 |          - | changes for speech 101
  v0.00 |          - | Initial version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:student-permission&#34;&gt;Many thanks to the students who have given me permission to use examples based on their work. Student consent forms are on file.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:student-permission&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Presentation</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/support-assignment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; You will deliver a presentation where you inform your
audience on a subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; All presentations benefit from using a variety of forms of
evidence from a variety of sources. This presentation provides a good
opportunity to practice finding and incorporating a variety of forms of
evidence from multiple sources and incorporating that information with
appropriate citations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Length:&lt;/strong&gt;  6 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due:&lt;/strong&gt; See the calendar for your section for due dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detailed-description&#34;&gt;Detailed Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locate an official US Federal, State, or Local Government report that is
about 20 pages long or longer. Prepare an informative presentation to
inform your audience on a subject &lt;strong&gt;related to&lt;/strong&gt; key findings included in
this report. &lt;strong&gt;You should not be summarizing the report&lt;/strong&gt;, you are only
using this report as &lt;strong&gt;one source&lt;/strong&gt; of evidence to support &lt;strong&gt;your&lt;/strong&gt;
informative argument, which should not be the same as the informative
argument this source is making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The report must be about 20 pages long or longer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The report must be less than 3 years old&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must include at least 2 additional sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must use a PowerPoint-style visual aid which uses the
assertion-evidence structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your presentation will be a live presentation delivered face-to-face in
front of your audience in an extemporaneous fashion. This format applies
to presentations delivered in-class and presentations &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/video-submission/&#34;&gt;submitted by
video&lt;/a&gt;. You should be practiced and
prepared for the presentation, but should not memorize the presentation or
read from a manuscript. You may use a key word/phrase outline on note
cards as speaking notes for this presentation if you will find them
helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is graded out of 150 points. 25 points come from the
preparation outline, 25 points come from the graded PowerPoint, and 100
points come from the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-rubric&#34;&gt;Outline Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outline portion of this assignment is worth 25 points. (Yes, you get
a sneaky bonus point! Shh, it&amp;rsquo;s not a math class!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Voice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written as the presenter would speak to the audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in complete sentences, but not in a spoken style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline has occasional sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Complete and effective introduction, supported main points, and conclusion, all separated by effective transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction, supported main points, or conclusion are ineffective. All transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction or conclusion incomplete. Supported main points. Some transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sections or transitions are missing or main points are not supported.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline Principles&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline follows the principles of parallelism, coordination, subordination, and division.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks one of the outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks no more than two outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks multiple outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;In-text Citations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and mostly written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and are written using APA/MLA style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are not present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Reference Section&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly and in APA format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed, but have errors.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are not listed or are listed incorrectly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses a professional 12 point font, double spaced. Effective and consistent numbering and indentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one minor inconsistency in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one major inconsistency or two minor inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Multiple inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Evidence with citation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing is plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;graded-powerpoint-rubric&#34;&gt;Graded PowerPoint Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The graded PowerPoint portion of this assignment is worth 25 points. (Yes,
you get a sneaky bonus point! Shh, it&amp;rsquo;s not a math class!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Supports the Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses a variety of types of visual evidence to support assertions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses visual evidence to support assertions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Majority of slides are text only.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No visual evidence included.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Professional&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The visual aid has a unified visual style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fonts, colors, and presentation of visual evidence are consistent on most slides.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fonts, colors, and presentation of visual evidence are inconsistent.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Contents of slides are inappropriate for professional use.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References and Citations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations and complete reference information for all evidence in the visual in APA format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations included for most evidence in the visual aid. Complete reference information included.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Majority of evidence is missing citation &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; reference information.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citation &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing throughout visual aid.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Accessible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that are accessible and appropriate for a general audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that hinder usability for some audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that hinder usability for average audience&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Significant problems with accessibility. Slides not useful for average audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Formatted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;All content slides use Assertion-Evidence structure.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;One error in Assertion-Evidence structure appears on one content slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;One error in Assertion-Evidence structure appears on multiple content slides.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Content slides have multiple errors of many kinds.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Evidence with citation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing is plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-rubric&#34;&gt;Presentation Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation portion of this assignment is worth 100 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;20 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;15 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;5 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Topic Fit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is compelling and interesting for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment or audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is inappropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is compelling and adds to the presentation. Complete and effective introduction, conclusion, and transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is clear. Complete introduction and conclusion. Transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of organization unclear. Portions of introduction or conclusion missing. One transition missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No organization clear to audience. Significant problems with introduction or conclusion. Transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points are effectively supported. Evidence cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points supported. Most evidence is cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis not supported by main points or support for main points missing. Citations for evidence are incomplete.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and/or main points missing. No citations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delivery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Verbally fluent and nonverbally engaging.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Minor issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would not distract a general audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Distracting issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would distract many audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Significant delivery issues that prevent even motivated audience members from understanding.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Time Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 30 seconds of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 1 minute of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 2 minutes of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation significantly short or had to be stopped.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;!--
Here are some example outlines for support presentations given in this
class.[^student-permission]

[Example Mediated Outline
1](/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-outline-example-1.docx) is
a well-formatted outline.

[![Example Mediated Outline 1](/img/course/mediated-outline-example-1.PNG)](/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-mediated-outline-1.docx)

[Example Mediated Outline
2](/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-outline-example-2.docx)
does a very good job with using oral citations throughout the
presentation.

[![Example Mediated Outline 2](/img/course/mediated-outline-example-2.PNG)](/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-mediated-outline-2.docx)
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/visual-aid/example-visual-aid.pptx&#34;&gt;example of a visual
aid&lt;/a&gt; that uses
the Assertion-Evidence structure for each of the three forms of evidence
which are commonly presented visually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/visual-aid/example-visual-aid.pptx&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/course/example-visual-aid.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Example Visual
Aid&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Here is an example mediated presentation that has been prepared using a narrated PowerPoint presentation.


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/9oiPG1VIzR4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;acknowledgments&#34;&gt;Acknowledgments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to TJ Kimble for his improvements to this assignment, incorporated beginning in v0.05.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- Links --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v2.05 | 2019-08-08 | Changes for Hugo compatibility, integrated and updated rubrics
  v2.04 | 2018-01-16 | moved presentation specific components to standalone assignment
  v2.03 | 2017-10-03 | Added text for choosing a topic
  v2.01 | 2017-09-12 | Added link to preparation outline assignment and example outlines
  v2.00 | 2017-08-15 | transitioned to star system
  v1.02 |          - | removed submission to Moodle
  v1.01 |          - | calendar no longer in course annex
  v1.00 |          - | Changes for block 2
  v0.05 |          - | changes to Other Requirements section, as suggested by TJ Kimble
  v0.04 |          - | added link to resource for citations in presentations
  v0.03 |          - | fixed relative links
  v0.02 |          - | changes for speech 101
  v0.01 |          - | corrected objective listed in final paragraph
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persuasive Presentation</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/persuasive-assignment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; You will deliver a presentation where you persuade your
audience on a subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Using all the techniques and strategies you learned in class,
you will prepare and deliver a persuasive speech. Your speech should be
appropriate for a professional audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Length:&lt;/strong&gt; 8 minutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due:&lt;/strong&gt; See the calendar for your section for due dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detailed-description&#34;&gt;Detailed Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a persuasion speech. You can select any topic (remembering who
your audience is). Be sure that there is a specific proposal or call for
action/change in your speech. You must state this clearly so your
audience knows exactly what you want of them. Maintain a focus on this
proposal. When you finish your presentation, many of the members of your
audience should have been persuaded to take the action you described in
your call to action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must use Monroe&amp;rsquo;s Motivated Sequence to organize your presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must use &lt;strong&gt;at least two&lt;/strong&gt; presentation aids in your speech.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One aid &lt;strong&gt;must be&lt;/strong&gt; a PowerPoint-style visual aid which uses the
&lt;strong&gt;assertion-evidence structure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One aid may be &lt;strong&gt;any other kind&lt;/strong&gt; of presentation aid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your presentation will be a live presentation delivered face-to-face in
front of your audience in an extemporaneous fashion. This format applies
to presentations delivered in-class and presentations &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/video-submission/&#34;&gt;submitted by
video&lt;/a&gt;. You should be practiced and
prepared for the presentation, but should not memorize the presentation or
read from a manuscript. You may use a key word / phrase outline on note
cards as speaking notes for this presentation if you will find them
helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is graded out of 125 points. 25 points come from the
preparation outline and 100 points come from the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-rubric&#34;&gt;Outline Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outline portion of this assignment is worth 25 points. (Yes, you get
a sneaky bonus point! Shh, it&amp;rsquo;s not a math class!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Voice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written as the presenter would speak to the audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in complete sentences, but not in a spoken style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline has occasional sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Complete and effective introduction, supported main points, and conclusion, all separated by effective transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction, supported main points, or conclusion are ineffective. All transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction or conclusion incomplete. Supported main points. Some transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sections or transitions are missing or main points are not supported.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline Principles&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline follows the principles of parallelism, coordination, subordination, and division.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks one of the outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks no more than two outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks multiple outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;In-text Citations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and mostly written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and are written using APA/MLA style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are not present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Reference Section&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly and in APA format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed, but have errors.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are not listed or are listed incorrectly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses a professional 12 point font, double spaced. Effective and consistent numbering and indentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one minor inconsistency in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one major inconsistency or two minor inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Multiple inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Evidence with citation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing is plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;presentation-rubric&#34;&gt;Presentation Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation portion of this assignment is worth 100 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;20 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;15 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;5 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Topic Fit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is compelling and interesting for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment or audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is inappropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is compelling and adds to the presentation. Complete and effective introduction, conclusion, and transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is clear. Complete introduction and conclusion. Transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of organization unclear. Portions of introduction or conclusion missing. One transition missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No organization clear to audience. Significant problems with introduction or conclusion. Transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points are effectively supported. Evidence cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points supported. Most evidence is cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis not supported by main points or support for main points missing. Citations for evidence are incomplete.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and/or main points missing. No citations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delivery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Verbally fluent and nonverbally engaging.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Minor issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would not distract a general audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Distracting issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would distract many audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Significant delivery issues that prevent even motivated audience members from understanding.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Time Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 30 seconds of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 1 minute of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 2 minutes of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation significantly short or had to be stopped.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example outline for a persuasive presentation given in this class.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:student-permission&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:student-permission&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-monroes-motivated-sequence-outline-1.docx&#34;&gt;Example Persuasive Outline 1&lt;/a&gt; is a well-formatted outline which uses Monroe&amp;rsquo;s Motivated Sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-monroes-motivated-sequence-outline-1.docx&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/course/example-monroes-motivated-sequence-outline-1.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;Example Persuasive Outline 1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- todo
[![Example Persuasive Outline 2](/images/example-monroes-motivated-sequence-outline-2.PNG)](/resources/example-asynchronous-outline-2.docx)

[Example Persuasive Outline 2](/resources/example-monroes-motivated-sequence-outline-2.docx) does a very good job with using oral citations throughout the presentation. --&gt;

&lt;!-- todo

Here is an example asynchronous presentation that has been prepared using a narrated PowerPoint presentation.


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/9oiPG1VIzR4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


--&gt;

&lt;!--
Acknowledgments
===============
--&gt;

&lt;!-- Links --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v2.05 | 2019-08-08 | Changes for Hugo compatibility, integrated and updated rubrics
  v2.04 | 2018-01-16 | moved presentation specific components to standalone assignment
  v2.03 | 2017-10-03 | Added text for choosing a topic
  v2.01 | 2017-09-12 | Added link to preparation outline assignment
  v2.00 | 2017-08-15 | transitioned to star system
  v1.03 | 2017-04-24 | Typos, clarification language, removed audience requirement
  v1.02 |          - | calendar has been moved out of course annex
  v1.01 |          - | repaired presentation video link, minor text fixes
  v1.00 |          - | changes for block 2
  v0.02 |          - | Fixed relative links
  v0.01 |          - | changes for speech 101
  v0.00 |          - | Initial version
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:student-permission&#34;&gt;Many thanks to the students who have given me permission to use examples based on their work. Student consent forms are on file.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:student-permission&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debate Assignment</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/debate-assignment/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This assignment is under construction&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; You will conduct a debate as a team of three people against
another team of three people. You will have approximately 20 minutes to
prepare before the debate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Being an agile and confident speaker who can think on his or
her feet is beneficial. Practice in debate requires you to demonstrate the
majority of the learning outcomes for this course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Length:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 minute maximum, per speaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due:&lt;/strong&gt; See the calendar for your section for due dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detailed-description&#34;&gt;Detailed Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The debate consists of a series of persuasive speeches argued as a team.
You can select any approach within the theme for the round. You do not
need to include a presentation aid in these speeches. &lt;strong&gt;When you finish
your presentation, the members of your audience should have been persuaded
to vote in favor of your side.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No new arguments may be presented in rebuttal speeches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your presentation will be part of a live debate as a team against an
opposing team. The debate will be delivered face-to-face in front of your
audience in an extemporaneous fashion. You may use any notes you wish, as
long as they have been prepared during the preparation time or during the
debate itself. You and your team mate will have 20 minutes to prepare for
the debate with the assistance of some additional class members after the
topic is announced. After preparation each member of the group will speak:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Group&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Speaker&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Speech&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Time Limit&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Constructive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CON&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Constructive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Constructive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CON&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Constructive&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CON&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rebuttal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;PRO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rebuttal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 minutes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;!-- Normal time limits
Group Member | Speech       | Time Limit
-------------|--------------|-----------
   PM        | Constructive | 7 minutes
   LO        | Constructive | 8 minutes
   MG        | Constructive | 8 minutes
   MO        | Constructive | 8 minutes
   LO        | Rebuttal     | 4 minutes
   PM        | Rebuttal     | 5 minutes
--&gt;

&lt;!--
Grading
=======

This project is graded out of 100 points. 30 points come from the
preparation time, and 70 points come from the presentation.

Preparation Rubric
------------------

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;8 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;6 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;4 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2 points&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
&lt;/table

Presentation Rubric
-------------------

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;10 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;8 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;6 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;4 points&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;2 points&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Analysis &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Support&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Clash&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Audience&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Adaptation&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;Delivery&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

--&gt;

&lt;!--
Examples
========

Here is an example debate.[^student-permission]


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/9oiPG1VIzR4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

--&gt;

&lt;!--
Acknowledgments
===============
--&gt;

&lt;!--
--&gt;

&lt;!-- Links --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v0.02 | 2018-08-08 | Changes for Hugo Compatibility
  v0.01 | 2018-01-16 | moved back to point system
  v0.00 | 2017-11-10 | Initial version

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Evaluations</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/peer-evaluations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/peer-evaluations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; You will provide feedback to other students in the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; Critically evaluating presentations is a key competency of
this course, as is effectively providing and incorporating feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Length:&lt;/strong&gt;
 * Traditional courses: one 3x5 note card per presenter.
 * Online/Hybrid courses: five paragraphs for one presenter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due:&lt;/strong&gt;
 * Traditional courses: peer feedback is completed during the in-class
   presentations.
 * Online/Hybrid courses: peer feedback is due no later than two days
   after the presentation due date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detailed-description&#34;&gt;Detailed Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traditional courses:&lt;/strong&gt; Your peer evaluation will be written on a note
card during each presentation. You will write a short paragraph or series
of bullet points containing feedback on their performance in your assigned
area of feedback. Students will be assigned to a topic for feedback
randomly from the following four options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assignment objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research and evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online/Hybrid courses:&lt;/strong&gt; Your peer evaluation will be delivered as
a text post in a forum on the course management system website. You will
reply to the video linked by your partner with several paragraphs
addressing their performance in the presentation. You should write at
least one paragraph with multiple sentences addressing each of the
required sections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivery Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research and Evidence Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective Evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your peer feedback will be evaluated based on the quality and usefulness
of the feedback for the presenter. Peer feedback should demonstrate each
of the four principles of effective feedback:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specific&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actionable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paired (Balanced)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;peer-feedback-rubric&#34;&gt;Peer Feedback Rubric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;7 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Feedback follows all four principles of effective feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Feedback does not follow one principle of effective feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Feedback does not follow two principles of effective feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Feedback does not follow more than two principles of effective feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;!--
Examples
========
--&gt;

&lt;!--
Here are some example outlines for mediated presentations given in this
class.[^student-permission]

[Example Mediated Outline
1](/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-outline-example-1.docx) is
a well-formatted outline.
--&gt;

&lt;!--
Acknowledgments
===============

[^student-permission] Many thanks to the students who have given me permission to use examples based on their work. Student consent forms are on file.
--&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v1.01 | 2019-08-08 | Updates for Hugo compatibility
  v1.00 | 2017-04-03 | Description for in-class vs. online feedback 
  v0.00 |          - | Initial version

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing Presentation Topics</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/presentation-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/presentation-topics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Picking a topic is one of the hardest parts of putting together
a presentation, and it is one of the most important. Getting off to
a strong start with a good topic that you find interesting will make the
research you need to do to put together a strong presentation fun, it will
make it easier for you to speak passionately to your audience, and it will
make it easier to put together a presentation the audience will listen to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;brainstorming-topics&#34;&gt;Brainstorming Topics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step one is coming up with a large number of topics to evaluate.
I generally recommend that students consider &lt;strong&gt;at least 100 topics&lt;/strong&gt; in
for each presentation they give in my classes. Coming up with that many
topics can be difficult, so I put together some &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/brainstorming-topics-for-presentations/&#34;&gt;tips for brainstorming
topics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;evaluating-topics&#34;&gt;Evaluating Topics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have an extensive list of topics, then you want to evaluate them.
When evaluating topics, be sure to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The assignment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your expertise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topics that are more specific are nearly always better than general topics.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;topics-to-avoid&#34;&gt;Topics to Avoid&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After many years of experience teaching Public Speaking, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that
there are some topics that rarely result in high-quality student work.
I &lt;strong&gt;strongly&lt;/strong&gt; advise you to avoid the topics listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controversial-or-political-issues&#34;&gt;Controversial or Political Issues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples include (but are not limited to):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gun Control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gay Marriage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abortion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Euthanasia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Death Penalty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marijuana&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any Religious Belief&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paying College Athletes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title IX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowering the Drinking Age

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually, anything to do with drinking (even “wine is good for you”). I’m tired of hearing about drinking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-people-already-know-they-should-or-should-not-do&#34;&gt;Things People Already Know They Should or Should Not Do&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples include (but are not limited to):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting Enough Sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wearing Seat Belts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular Exercise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand Washing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blood Donation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organ Donation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tobacco Use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drug Use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not Driving While Distracted (ex: Texting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anything About Diet, for example:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eating Healthy Diets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drinking more Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eating Breakfast&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:nyt-breakfast-takedown-2016&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:nyt-breakfast-takedown-2016&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat This&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop Eating This&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any “Green” Topic, for example:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recycling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserving Water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conserving Electricity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing Fuel Usage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Scary Chemical&amp;rdquo; Presentation&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:way-dhmo&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:way-dhmo&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speech-topics-that-are-not-creative-or-unique&#34;&gt;Speech Topics That Are Not Creative or Unique&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples include (but are not limited to):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The “Disease of the Week” Speech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nanotechnology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genetically Modified Foods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genetically Modified Organisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaccination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pet Adoption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal Cruelty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal Testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fraternity/Sorority Speeches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v0.04 | 2019-08-08 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.03 | 2017-10-11 | Clarified tobacco and drug use
  v0.02 | 2017-10-02 | Added in the &#34;scary chemical&#34; speech.
  v0.01 | 2017-04-11 | Sources for breakfast
  v0.00 | 2017-03-06 | Initial version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:nyt-breakfast-takedown-2016&#34;&gt;Especially since there is no scientific evidence that clearly demonstrates a benefit to eating breakfast unless you are hungry.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:carroll-2016&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:carroll-2016&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:nyt-breakfast-takedown-2016&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:way-dhmo&#34;&gt;Especially since &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; is a chemical.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:acs-2017&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:acs-2017&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; These arguments are brilliantly satired by Tom Way in his advocacy against &amp;ldquo;Dihydrogen Monoxide&amp;rdquo; (H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O – plain water) on his website.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:dhmo-website&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:dhmo-website&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:way-dhmo&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:carroll-2016&#34;&gt;Carroll, A. E. (2016, May 23). Sorry, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing magical about breakfast. &lt;em&gt;The New York Times.&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/24/upshot/sorry-theres-nothing-magical-about-breakfast.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/24/upshot/sorry-theres-nothing-magical-about-breakfast.html&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:carroll-2016&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:acs-2017&#34;&gt;American Chemistry Society. (2017). &lt;em&gt;Chemistry Is Everywhere.&lt;/em&gt; Retrieved October 2, 2017, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.acs.org/content/acs/en/education/whatischemistry/everywhere.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.acs.org/content/acs/en/education/whatischemistry/everywhere.html&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:acs-2017&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:dhmo-website&#34;&gt;Way, T. (n.d.). &lt;em&gt;Facts About Dihydrogen Monoxide&lt;/em&gt; [Satire]. Retrieved October 2, 2017, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dhmo.org/facts.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.dhmo.org/facts.html&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:dhmo-website&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citations in Presentation Aids</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/citations-in-presentation-aids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/citations-in-presentation-aids/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You should always cite your sources both in print and in prepared
presentations. Citing your sources significantly improves your credibility
and also protects you from committing plagiarism. When citing information
in a presentation, the citation should always appear in the same channel
as the information. For example, information you put on a slide should
have a citation on that slide and information you say aloud should be
accompanied by an oral citation. If you have information on a slide and
say it out loud, then there should be a citation in both channels. The
information on this page focuses on citations in presentation aids. I also
have a detailed resource on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/oral-citations-in-presentations/&#34;&gt;Oral Citations in Presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This resource covers how to cite complete works (such as images, audio,
and video) and how to cite information only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;citing-information-in-presentation-aids&#34;&gt;Citing Information in Presentation Aids&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many standardized ways to cite sources in print, and you should
pick one of these to use as part of any presentation aids that can include
print. The most commonly used style guides in academic writing are
published by the American Psychological Association (APA)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:APA&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:APA&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and the
Modern Language Association (MLA)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:MLA&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:MLA&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. An addition widely used style
guide is the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Manual of Style&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Chicago&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Chicago&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. A variation of Chicago
Style designed specifically for students and scholars is also occasionally
encountered, and is commonly referred to by the last name of its
originator, Turabian&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Turabian&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Turabian&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The Online Writing Lab (OWL) at Purdue
University maintains a set of popular online resources for [APA]&lt;a href=&#34;https://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/560/01/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;APA
Formatting and Style Guide&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/747/01/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/717/01/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Chicago&lt;/a&gt; styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-on-slides&#34;&gt;Information on Slides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For visual aids that rely on slides, such as PowerPoint, it is usually
best to adapt citation requirements from an established style guide for
print, such as those discussed above. These typically only require minimal
adaptation. My standard advice is to use brief, in-text style citations on
your main slides, and use full citations in a set of reference slides at
the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, place a brief, in-text style citation next to the information being
cited on the slide. If there is not enough space next to the information
it may be appropriate to footnotes within each slide. Second, place full
citations in their own dedicated references slide at the end of the
presentation. Use multiple reference slides if needed so that references
will be legible to your audience. There may be times when other approaches
are more appropriate, such as providing the full citation on each slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are citing information only this is all you need to do, but &lt;strong&gt;if
you are citing a complete work, such as an image, you will need to do
more! Continue reading!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-on-handouts&#34;&gt;Information on Handouts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For handouts, provide citations exactly as you would for a normal text
document. In order to conserve paper and improve visual appeal, you may
choose to place citations and references directly on the handout rather
than starting them in a separate section on a new page as most style
guides recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;using-copyrighted-work-in-presentation-aids&#34;&gt;Using Copyrighted Work in Presentation Aids&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some types of work providing a citation isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Copyrighted
works belong to someone, and that person has the right to decide when and
how their work gets used. Citing the source of copyrighted work is not the
same as having permission to use the work. &lt;strong&gt;Using copyrighted work,
including images, videos, and audio without permission (such as a license)
is usually illegal, even with citations,&lt;/strong&gt; unless that usage is permitted
under legal exemptions to the exclusive rights of copyright holders in all
applicable jurisdictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the United States, the majority of these exemptions are listed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/chapter-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17
U.S. Code Chapter
1&lt;/a&gt;. As a student or
educator, many uses are permitted under &lt;strong&gt;Fair Use&lt;/strong&gt;, described in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/107&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;17
U.S. Code § 107&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my classes, I require students to explicitly identify the license or
source of their right to use a copyrighted work. &lt;strong&gt;Fair Use should only be
identified as a source of this right in classes I teach when the work and
all similar works are not available under any free license and it legally
applies.&lt;/strong&gt; This is important practice for future employment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;citing-images&#34;&gt;Citing Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking images and using them without citation is plagiarism.&lt;/strong&gt; Images
should be cited in accordance with the requirements of the copyright
holder. In my classes I require citations for images to be accompanied by
a statement that identifies the source of the right to use the image. The
published APA style guide does not establish standards for a full citation
to use with images, but the APA Style Blog has published &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.apastyle.org/apastyle/2010/04/theres-an-art-to-it.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;examples of
citations for works of art&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:http-blog-apastyle-org-apastyle-2010-04-theres-an-art-to-it-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:http-blog-apastyle-org-apastyle-2010-04-theres-an-art-to-it-html&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
Based on those examples, here is a sample the full citation for an image
that would go on a references slide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miller, K. D. (2016, October 14). &lt;em&gt;Outlining&lt;/em&gt; [Digital Photograph].
Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140911330@N07/29696952664/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140911330@N07/29696952664/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;citing-audio&#34;&gt;Citing Audio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should provide a full oral citation either before or after an audio
presentation aid. Using only a printed citation for an audio presentation
aid is not appropriate because it does not match the channel of the
information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;citing-video&#34;&gt;Citing Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video uses both audio and visual channels, and should be cited in both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;citing-artifacts-and-objects&#34;&gt;Citing Artifacts and Objects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artifacts and objects typically do not require citations, but
acknowledgments of their source are often appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Resource Links --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v1.01 | 2019-08-15 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v1.00 | 2017-09-04 | forked this reference from the oral citation reference
  v0.07 | 2017-03-09 | fixed reference link
  v0.06 |          - | Added examples of image citations from APA Style Blog
  v0.05 |          - | Created a header for End Notes
  v0.04 |          - | Added significant information on citations in presentation aids
  v0.03 |          - | Added resource links for print citation formats
  v0.02 |          - | Corrected bullet list formatting
  v0.01 |          - | Corrected footnote link formatting
  v0.00 |          - | Initial version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:APA&#34;&gt;American Psychological Association (Ed.). (2010). &lt;em&gt;Publication manual of the American Psychological Association&lt;/em&gt; (6th ed.). Washington, DC: American Psychological Association.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:APA&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:MLA&#34;&gt;Modern Language Association of America (Ed.). (2016). &lt;em&gt;MLA Handbook&lt;/em&gt; (8th ed.). New York: The Modern Language Association of America.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:MLA&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Chicago&#34;&gt;University of Chicago Press Staff (Ed.). (2010). &lt;em&gt;The Chicago manual of style&lt;/em&gt; (16th ed.). Chicago: The University of Chicago Press.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Chicago&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Turabian&#34;&gt;Turabian, K. L., Booth, W. C., Colomb, G. G., &amp;amp; Williams, J. M. (2013). &lt;em&gt;A manual for writers of research papers, theses, and dissertations: Chicago Style for students and researchers&lt;/em&gt; (8th edition). Chicago: University of Chicago Press.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Turabian&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:http-blog-apastyle-org-apastyle-2010-04-theres-an-art-to-it-html&#34;&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:http-blog-apastyle-org-apastyle-2010-04-theres-an-art-to-it-html&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oral Citations</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/oral-citations-in-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/oral-citations-in-presentations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You should always cite your sources both in print and in prepared
presentations. Citing your sources significantly improves your credibility
and also protects you from committing plagiarism. When citing information
in a presentation, the citation should always appear in the same channel
as the information. For example, information you put on a slide should
have a citation on that slide and information you say aloud should be
accompanied by an oral citation. If you have information on a slide and
say it out loud, then there should be a citation in both channels. The
information on this page focuses on oral citations in a presentation.
I also have a detailed resource on the use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/citations-in-presentation-aids/&#34;&gt;Citations in Presentation
Aids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;oral-citations&#34;&gt;Oral Citations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike citations in print, where standards are well established, oral
citations are a bit trickier. They need to contain much of the same
information as print citations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-time-a-source-is-cited&#34;&gt;The First Time a Source is Cited&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first oral citation to a source has the same function as the full
reference to the source that would go in a reference section at the end of
a paper. An oral citation should always include as much of the following
information as possible the first time that you cite it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author’s name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author’s credibility (Who is this person? Why are they qualified
on this subject?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The type of source (Editorial, News Article, Book, TV Show, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title of the piece (Article title, Book title, Episode title, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title of what it is in (Title of Newspaper, Webpage, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date that it was published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every direct quotation should include a page number (or equivalent
information)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Antoinette M. Burton, an American historian and Professor of History
and of Global and Transnational Studies at the University of Illinois,
argues that British influence became powerful in India due to the
British being successful pioneers in the industrial and technological
world in her 1994 book &lt;em&gt;Burdens of History: British Feminists, Indian
Women, and Imperial Culture, 1865–1915&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:burton-1994&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:burton-1994&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;each-time-the-source-is-cited-after&#34;&gt;Each Time the Source is Cited After&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, whenever you bring up new information in the same source, you only
need to make sure we know where you got it, but you don’t need to give us
all of the same information again. These subsequent citations have the
same function as the brief in-text citations that go throughout a paper.
You can say things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Burton&amp;rsquo;s book also argues…&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“She goes on to say…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“In the same article…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“But Davis takes issue with this point…”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Samir quotes Bill Clinton as saying ‘…’”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember: every direct quotation should include a page number (or equivalent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;watch-out-for-these-mistakes&#34;&gt;Watch out for These Mistakes!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be certain you are citing the right thing. If someone is quoted in an
article then you should say that they were quoted in the article – you
should not cite them directly!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you are putting citations in your outline or on your speaking
notes&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:citations-on-speaking-notes&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:citations-on-speaking-notes&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, you should write them as you
would speak them during a presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t leave out significant information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Always cite information in the same channel it is presented in&lt;/em&gt;
(spoken vs. on a presentation aid)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t place &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of your citations in your visual aid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not use the credibility statement in your introduction as an &amp;ldquo;oral
reference section&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Resource Links --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v1.01 | 2019-08-15 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v1.00 | 2017-09-04 | forked resource to focus on oral citations here and citations in presentation aids in a separate resource
  v0.07 | 2017-03-09 | fixed reference link
  v0.06 |          - | Added examples of image citations from APA Style Blog
  v0.05 |          - | Created a header for End Notes
  v0.04 |          - | Added significant information on citations in presentation aids
  v0.03 |          - | Added resource links for print citation formats
  v0.02 |          - | Corrected bullet list formatting
  v0.01 |          - | Corrected footnote link formatting
  v0.00 |          - | Initial version
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:burton-1994&#34;&gt;Burton, A. M. (1994). &lt;em&gt;Burdens of history: British feminists, Indian women, and imperial culture, 1885–1915.&lt;/em&gt; Chapel Hill, NC: University of North Carolina Press.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:burton-1994&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:citations-on-speaking-notes&#34;&gt;This applies to all forms of speaking notes, whether they are on note cards, printed sheets of paper, cue cards, manuscripts, etc.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:citations-on-speaking-notes&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video Submission</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/video-submission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/assignment/video-submission/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt; A video of you presenting in front of an audience of at
least 5 adults. This is required for online classes and is optional for
speakers who have a conflict with the in-class presentation date in
traditional classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt; If you are taking the class online or are submitting
a presentation outside of a traditional class meeting, you will need to be
able to submit your presentation by video instead of delivering it in
person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due:&lt;/strong&gt; Presentation video due dates are the same as for the assignment.
See the course calendar for assignment due dates. Presentation videos
turned in after the assignment due date will be considered late unless the
absence is &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt; excused &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; cannot be planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submission Checklist:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Upload video to YouTube&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Submit link to YouTube video to the assignment on Moodle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Upload presentation aid files (if any) to the assignment on Moodle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detailed-description&#34;&gt;Detailed Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;format&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To submit a presentation video you will need to prepare and post a video
of your presentation on YouTube. The video must show the entire audience
of 5 adults both &lt;strong&gt;before and after&lt;/strong&gt; the presentation. The video needs to
show the &lt;strong&gt;majority of the presenter&amp;rsquo;s body&lt;/strong&gt; from the beginning of the
presentation until the end of the presentation. The video must be recorded
in a single, continuous shot – not edited in any way. Audio and video
quality must be clear enough to be graded. YouTube videos may be set to
&lt;strong&gt;public&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;unlisted&lt;/strong&gt;, but &lt;strong&gt;cannot be turned in if they are uploaded
as private.&lt;/strong&gt; I recommend that you choose to upload your videos as
&amp;ldquo;unlisted&amp;rdquo; videos. You may chose to switch the accessibility of these
videos to &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; (recommended) or delete them (not recommended) once
the presentation assignment has been graded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;required-sections&#34;&gt;Required Sections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A view of the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A view of the audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presentation videos are graded according to the exact same criteria as
in-person presentations. See each specific assignment for grading
criteria. &lt;strong&gt;Videos that do not meet requirements posted above, or which
have problems that make them ungradable, will score a zero and cannot be
resubmitted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;common-problems-with-videos&#34;&gt;Common Problems with Videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul style=&#34;list-style: none;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Audience not shown at beginning and/or end of video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Not enough people in the audience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Audio too quiet to hear&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Noise during the presentation makes it inaudible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Poor audio quality that prevents understanding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Video not clear enough to see presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Video does not show the majority of the presenter&#39;s body&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Presenter leaves the frame of the video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Visual aids are not shown in the video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ Portions of video are missing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ The video has been edited&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;☐ The video is uploaded but set to private, so no one else can see it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!--
Examples
========

Here are some example outlines for mediated presentations given in this class.[^student-permission]

[Example Mediated Outline 1](/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-outline-example-1.docx) is a well-formatted outline.

[![Example Mediated Outline 1](/img/course/mediated-outline-example-1.PNG)](/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-mediated-outline-1.docx)

[Example Mediated Outline 2](/course/public-speaking/assignment/mediated-outline-example-2.docx) does a very good job with using oral citations throughout the presentation.

[![Example Mediated Outline 2](/img/course/mediated-outline-example-2.PNG)](/course/public-speaking/assignment/example-mediated-outline-2.docx)

Here is an example mediated presentation that has been prepared using a narrated PowerPoint presentation.


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/9oiPG1VIzR4&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

--&gt;

&lt;!--
Acknowledgments
===============
--&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!--
--&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v0.04 | 2019-08-08 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.03 |          - | Clarified timing for early vs. late submissions, minor formatting changes
  v0.02 |          - | Reduced requirement to 5 adult audience members
  v0.01 |          - | Added text about private videos
  v0.00 |          - | Initial version

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/course-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/course-overview/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand the organization of the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students know how to succeed in the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students are introduced and have contact info for peers in the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; This lesson orients students to the new class and to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copies of Syllabus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index Cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being Prepared for Class

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study Routine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syllabus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course Structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attendance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moodle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to Succeed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group students into groups of 3-4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students share information about themselves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students introduce each other to the class (round robin)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students put their information on index cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students copy peer contact information into notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students turn in their contact information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review &amp;amp; Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strategic grouping may be necessary for improved peer mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v0.00 | 2019-08-07 | Initial Version

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic Selection</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/topic-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/topic-selection/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand how to analyze audiences, environments, and topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students learn the best ways to brainstorm topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students have a set of potential topics at the end of class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; The best presentations occur when the audience, the
environment, and the topic all work together. Most of the time you can
only influence some of these factors. It is important to be able to
analyze the factors you cannot influence so you can choose the best fit
for the aspects you can influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great presentations require an alignment of:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typically, you will not be able to influence them all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzing your audience

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demographics

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Age&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:both-average-and-range&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:both-average-and-range&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Race&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Socio-economic status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychological characteristics

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attitudes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beliefs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opinions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzing the presentation environment

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time of day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ecology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Context&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:audience-perspective&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:audience-perspective&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzing topics

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right for you

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting to you[^like-on-an-aiplane]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have expertise (or you know how to get it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right for your audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right for your situation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing a topic

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with a large number of options (100+)

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think in multiple sessions (10-15, 9x over 3 days)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk with other people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider personal experiences and interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research current events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze the best options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group students into groups of 5 students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student brainstorm a large number of potential topics for an upcoming presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students select the best topics for this class, and also for hypothetical audience-environment pairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires students to use notebook paper. Strategic grouping
may be necessary for improved peer mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:-----------------
  v0.01 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:both-average-and-range&#34;&gt;When considering age, make sure you think about both the average age and the overall range of ages.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:both-average-and-range&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:audience-perspective&#34;&gt;Think about context from the perspective of the audience. Where are they coming from? Where are they going next? What current events are they thinking about?
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:audience-perspective&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introductions, Transitions, and Conclusions</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/introductions-transitions-and-conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/introductions-transitions-and-conclusions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the essential components of an effective
introduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the common types of transition and the locations
where they are needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the essential components of an effective
conclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Effective introductions, transitions, and conclusions are
essential components of every presentation. They are essential for
establishing and maintaining audience attention throughout the
presentation. Introductions and conclusions are the portions of
presentations that audiences are most likely to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductions&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attention Getter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relevance Statement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Credibility Statement&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:these-are-arguments&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:these-are-arguments&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thesis Statement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of Main Points&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:roadmap&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:roadmap&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transitions&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of transition

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal summary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal preview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directional&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:this-does-both&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:this-does-both&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signposts with Transitions&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:signpost-examples&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:signpost-examples&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Placement

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Between intro and first main point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Between each main point in the body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Between last main point and conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summarized Main Points&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:optional&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:optional&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restated Thesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clincher&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:full-circle&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:full-circle&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group students into groups of 5 students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students create an introduction, transitions, and a conclusion for a presentation on &amp;ldquo;how to do&amp;rdquo; something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires students to use notebook paper and note cards.
Strategic grouping may be necessary for improved peer mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
 --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
technology usage will present an unreasonable burden may be accommodated
on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:-----------------
  v0.02 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.01 |          - | added description for overview
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:these-are-arguments&#34;&gt;Both your relevance statement and your credibility statement should really be called &amp;ldquo;arguments.&amp;rdquo; You need to show your audience evidence that the topic is relevant and you are credible. Don&amp;rsquo;t just say it!
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:these-are-arguments&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:roadmap&#34;&gt;This is the &amp;ldquo;roadmap&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;preview&amp;rdquo; of your presentation. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll start off by talking about foo, then I&amp;rsquo;ll explain bar.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:roadmap&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:this-does-both&#34;&gt;A directional transition includes both a summary and a preview. &amp;ldquo;Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve heard the main arguments in support of&amp;hellip;, let&amp;rsquo;s look at some of the counter-arguments.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:this-does-both&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:signpost-examples&#34;&gt;Examples of signpost transitions include &amp;ldquo;First&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Next&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;In conclusion.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:signpost-examples&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:optional&#34;&gt;Summarizing your main points is optional. You should do this if you think the audience might have trouble remembering them, like if you had a lot, or if the presentation was long.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:optional&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:full-circle&#34;&gt;A clincher that connects back to your introduction often works well, if you are having a hard time.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:full-circle&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preparation Outlines</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/preparation-outlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/preparation-outlines/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand that every presentation includes an introduction, body, and conclusion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students know the different types of outlines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students know the primary criteria for effective outlining.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students practice organizing points into an outline which meets these criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Preparing an outline will help you prepare, research, and
organize your presentation. Outlining is a key competency in Public
Speaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every presentation has three major sections:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conclusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of Outlines

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alphanumeric Outlines&lt;/strong&gt; vs. &lt;strong&gt;Decimal Outlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full-sentence outlines&lt;/strong&gt; vs. &lt;strong&gt;Topic Outlines&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:full-sentences-used&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:full-sentences-used&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outline Principles&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:tardiff-brizee-2013-FourMain&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:tardiff-brizee-2013-FourMain&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parallelism&lt;/strong&gt; (Writing all items in full sentences will fulfill this requirement.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coordination&lt;/strong&gt; (All items at the same level should have the same level of importance.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subordination&lt;/strong&gt; (Top-level items should be general and information deeper in the outline should be more specific.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Division&lt;/strong&gt; (Each item, if divided, should be divided into two or more parts.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group students into groups of 5 students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group creates a full-sentence outline for a presentation about &amp;ldquo;how to do something&amp;rdquo; (15 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups revise the outline to follow the 4 outline principles (5 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups transfer the outline onto note cards (one full-sentence item per note card)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups shuffle the note cards and pass their presentation to another group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups re-construct an outline from the cards (10 min)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups fix problems with the outline (5 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires students to use notebook paper and note cards.
Strategic grouping may be necessary for improved peer mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
writing by hand and moving physical objects will present an unreasonable
burden may be accommodated if necessary. Students may be placed in groups
strategically if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:-----------------
  v0.02 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo Compatibility
  v0.01 | 2017-03-09 | Corrected link in footnote
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:full-sentences-used&#34;&gt;Full sentence outlines are used in this class.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:full-sentences-used&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:tardiff-brizee-2013-FourMain&#34;&gt;Tardiff, E., &amp;amp; Brizee, A. (2013, March 1). Four Main Components for Effective Outlines. Retrieved October 12, 2016, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/544/01/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/544/01/&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:tardiff-brizee-2013-FourMain&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Informative Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-informative-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-informative-presentations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify each of the common informative organization
schemes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand common mistakes for each organization scheme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand how considering multiple organization schemes for
a topic improves presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Using a recognizable organization pattern through all of
the main points in a presentation makes it easier for the audience to
follow the presentation. Considering multiple organization patterns for
a topic often highlights different and more compelling approaches to the
presentation, and often more effective main points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A container to draw topics from&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion about the need for organization patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Informative Organization Patterns

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topical&lt;/strong&gt; (often overused)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chronological&lt;/strong&gt; (either direction)

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Causal&lt;/strong&gt; is a subtype, also either direction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spatial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro/Con&lt;/strong&gt; (easy to accidentally be persuasive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mnemonic Gimmick&lt;/strong&gt; (alliteration, rhyme, acronym, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing effective patterns

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to come up with main points that work for each pattern (brainstorm options, don&amp;rsquo;t just default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audience analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students brainstorm ten broad topics for presentations in groups of 4-5, writing each on an index card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students fold their topics in half and place them in the container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students in the next group down draw 3 topics from the container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students work as groups to create a set of full-sentence main points for a chronological, spatial, pro/con and mnemonic gimmick organizational pattern (4 sets of main points) &amp;ndash; 15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students create a thesis statement for each pattern that those main points would be evidence to support (4 thesis statements) – 5 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups share their thesis and main points, going around the room for each type of organization pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires note cards and student creativity. Students in the
class may work at dramatically different paces, which may require
strategic grouping or an opportunity to engage in pair work earlier in the
process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
technology usage will present an unreasonable burden will be accommodated
on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions
   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:---------------
  v0.03 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo Compatibility
  v0.02 |          - | revised activity for group work
  v0.01 |          - | Minor text fixes
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version
--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Evidence</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/supporting-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/supporting-evidence/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand how evidence supports other evidence in tiers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand the types of evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand where to find evidence to support their claims.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand the importance of using diverse forms of evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students know how to cite their evidence in presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; All presentations are built around a series of claims that
are supported by evidence. Presentation with well supported claims that
are addressed by several diverse forms of evidence are significantly more
effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector, personal devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claims require evidence. This evidence may also require evidence of its own&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supporting your claims&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:diversify-evidence&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:diversify-evidence&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of Evidence

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empirical Evidence&lt;/strong&gt; can be independently verified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testimonial Evidence&lt;/strong&gt; depends on the judgment of experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anecdotal Evidence&lt;/strong&gt; depends on personal experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analogical Evidence&lt;/strong&gt; shows how something unfamiliar is similar to something familiar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forms of evidence

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Numbers:&lt;/strong&gt; Statistics, Data, Charts, and Graphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People&amp;rsquo;s Words:&lt;/strong&gt; Quotations, Paraphrases, and Summaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things:&lt;/strong&gt; Artifacts, Examples, Photographs, and Illustrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stories:&lt;/strong&gt; Narrative, Personal Experiences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting evidence&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:diversify-sources&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:diversify-sources&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating evidence&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interviews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surveys&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding evidence&lt;/strong&gt; in credible print, media, and electronic sources

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding evidence means that what you find &lt;strong&gt;supports your claims, not finding a source that is making the same argument&lt;/strong&gt; as you. Your sources don&amp;rsquo;t have to be on the same subject as your presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of Sources

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scholarly Sources&lt;/strong&gt; are produced by academics and researchers. Nearly always have a bibliography.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Sources&lt;/strong&gt; are produced by experts in their own trades.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Popular Sources&lt;/strong&gt; are produced for a general audience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Sources&lt;/strong&gt; include Twitter and blog posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Biased Sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Search Tools&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:go-beyond-online-sources&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:go-beyond-online-sources&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced Search&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google News&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Scholar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Library

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holdings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inter-library Loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Databases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow Down!

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online versions of print sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citing your sources

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citations in outlines and on presentation aids

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-text and full citations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Citation Styles: &lt;strong&gt;APA,&lt;/strong&gt; MLA, Chicago/Turabian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The OWL at Purdue&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:OWL&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:OWL&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oral citations

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial citition

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Author’s name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The author’s credibility (Who is this person? Why are they qualified on this subject?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The type of source (Editorial, News Article, Book, TV Show, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title of the piece (Article title, Book title, Episode title, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title of what it is in (Title of Newspaper, Webpage, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date that it was published&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every direct quotation should include a page number (or equivalent information)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-visited citations, just make it clear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a news story online (10 minutes)

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify the types of evidence used&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss with your group (5 minutes)

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which forms of evidence were used?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which types of evidence were missing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did the author diversify their evidence?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What evidence should they add (and how can they find it)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires student access to online resources and personal
devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
technology usage will present an unreasonable burden may be accommodated
on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:-----------------
  v0.05 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.04 | 2017-03-09 | Moved discussion on citation here, re-ordered discussion around supporting an argument
  v0.03 |          - | Added discussion of types of Sources
  v0.02 |          - | Added discussion questions and clarified evidence sources don&#39;t have to be on the same topic
  v0.01 |          - | Corrected footnote for Purdue OWL
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:diversify-evidence&#34;&gt;Bottom Line: DIVERSIFY YOUR EVIDENCE.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:diversify-evidence&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:diversify-sources&#34;&gt;Bottom Line: DIVERSIFY YOUR SOURCES.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:diversify-sources&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:go-beyond-online-sources&#34;&gt;If all of your sources are webpages, you did it wrong.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:go-beyond-online-sources&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:OWL&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://owl.english.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://owl.english.purdue.edu/&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:OWL&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Aid Design</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-aid-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-aid-design/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: A version of the activity used in this lesson was presented at the
2018 Southern States Communication Association Conference. &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/talk/miller-pruim-2018-slides/&#34;&gt;See it
here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Science and Technical Communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify fundamentals of good slide design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the problems with the typical topic phrase and
bullet list presentation aid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students are able to use the assertion-evidence structure effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; The speed of information has increased dramatically in our
interconnected world. Social media, blogging, and other forms of
communication technology mean that crises appear and build momentum more
quickly than ever. Basic exposure to crisis response presentations is
essential because members of organizations never know when they may need
to be part of responding to a crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slides Against Humanity decks

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One deck with blanks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One deck with answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typesetting

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Size&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fonts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Font effects (shadow, bold, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No text should ever be longer than two lines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effects&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:only-meaningful-effects&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:only-meaningful-effects&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slide Transitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Topic Phrase and Bullet List Structure is Bad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Assertion-evidence Structure is Good!&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full-sentence assertion paired with visual evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved audience understanding of the topic&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:garner-alley-2013&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:garner-alley-2013&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved &lt;em&gt;presenter&lt;/em&gt; understanding&lt;/strong&gt; of the topic&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:garner-alley-2016&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:garner-alley-2016&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of visual evidence

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photographs, Images, Recordings (that is, things)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphs, Charts, Diagrams (numbers, presented visually)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct quotes (peoples&amp;rsquo; words)&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:must-be-evidence&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:must-be-evidence&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stories/Narratives&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:usually-multiple-slides&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:usually-multiple-slides&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual evidence &lt;strong&gt;must be cited visually&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work: Slides Against Humanity&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:miller-pruim-2018-slides&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:miller-pruim-2018-slides&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate student into two groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deal out cards to students

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group A gets cards from the deck with blanks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group B gets cards from the answer deck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create pairs of students, one from group A and one from group B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The students combine their cards to get a full-sentence assertion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students work together in pairs to create three content slides that provide visual evidence for assertions which support their claim.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students use an image as visual evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students use a chart or graph as visual evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students use a brief direct quotation as visual evidence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students present the slides that they have created&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires student access to online resources and personal
computers. Strategic grouping may be necessary for improved peer
mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
technology usage will present an unreasonable burden may be accommodated
on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:---------------
  v0.02 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.01 | 2017-09-13 | modified to create 3 content slides
  v0.00 | 2017-08-29 | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:only-meaningful-effects&#34;&gt;Effects should only be used in your visual aid if they &lt;em&gt;add meaning&lt;/em&gt; to the presentation.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:only-meaningful-effects&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:garner-alley-2013&#34;&gt;Garner, J. K., &amp;amp; Alley, M. P. (2013). How the Design of Presentation Slides Affects Audience Comprehension: A Case for the Assertion–Evidence Approach. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Engineering Education, 29&lt;/em&gt;(6), 1564–1579.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:garner-alley-2013&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:garner-alley-2016&#34;&gt;Garner, J. K., &amp;amp; Alley, M. P. (2016). Slide Structure Can Influence the Presenter’s Understanding of the Presentation’s Content. &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Engineering Education, 32&lt;/em&gt;(1), 39–54.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:garner-alley-2016&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:must-be-evidence&#34;&gt;Quotations are only visual evidence if they actually &lt;em&gt;are evidence for&lt;/em&gt; the claim you are making. Quotes that are pretty neat and kind-of related are not evidence. You should avoid using quotes like those in the body of your presentation.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:must-be-evidence&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:usually-multiple-slides&#34;&gt;When stories/narratives are used as examples, they typically are supported by multiple slides, often with other forms of visual evidence (pictures, charts, quotations, etc.).
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:usually-multiple-slides&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:miller-pruim-2018-slides&#34;&gt;This original teaching activity was presented at the 2018 Southern States Communication Association Conference. &lt;a href=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/talk/miller-pruim-2018-slides/&#34;&gt;See more information here!&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:miller-pruim-2018-slides&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plagiarism and Intellectual Property</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/plagiarism-and-intellectual-property/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/plagiarism-and-intellectual-property/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand the difference between copyrighted and public domain
material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can list the common types of Creative Commons licenses and
their meaning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand fair use and its limitations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand the difference between citing a work and having
license to use the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Avoiding plagiarism and theft is very important. There are
many ways to accidentally use content without providing proper citation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with Internet access for demonstration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one computer with Internet access per group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review citing sources and plagiarism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public domain

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Age&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public works, such as US government works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renounced/Waived Copyright (CC0, for example)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Licensing

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicit licensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fair Use from 17 USC § 107 &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:17-USC-107&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:17-USC-107&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;the fair use of a copyrighted work&amp;hellip;for purposes such as
&amp;gt; criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching (including multiple
&amp;gt; copies for classroom use), scholarship, or research, is not an
&amp;gt; infringement of copyright. In determining whether the use made of
&amp;gt; a work in any particular case is a fair use the factors to be
&amp;gt; considered shall include—
&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;  1. the purpose and character of the use, including whether such use is of a commercial nature or is for nonprofit educational purposes;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;  2. the nature of the copyrighted work;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;  3. the amount and substantiality of the portion used in relation to the copyrighted work as a whole; and&lt;br&gt;
&amp;gt;  4. the effect of the use upon the potential market for or value of the copyrighted work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concerns beyond legal concerns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course expectations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students get no practice or hands-on experience with citation in this
lesson plan. This lesson needs to be paired with an additional lesson
where citation and licensing are practiced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. This lesson relies
on online resources that are demonstrated visually through a projector.
Students who require accommodation may follow-along on their personal
devices, if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:---------------
  v0.03 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.02 | 2017-03-09 | Moved citation section to research and evidence lesson plan
  v0.01 |          - | Moved citation to footnote
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version 

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:17-USC-107&#34;&gt;17 USC § 107. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/107/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/107/&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:17-USC-107&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding and Using Images</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/finding-and-using-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/finding-and-using-images/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify a variety of sources for images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can evaluate images for different uses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can create slides and handouts which incorporate images
effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand how to cite images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand licensing and usage rights for copyrighted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can address accessibility concerns for images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Integrating images effectively is a vital part of
constructing a well-developed visual aid. Visual aids which use the
Assertion-Evidence Structure rely on images as one of their primary modes
of presenting visual evidence. Integrating images is an area that students
frequently struggle with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with Internet access for demonstration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one computer with Internet access per group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion of why we need to use images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction of sources

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://images.google.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Main_Page&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing effective images

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aspect Ratio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using images in PowerPoint-style presentations

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Licensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using images in handouts or other presentation aids

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Licensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accessibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students work in teams to create both a PowerPoint-style and
a handout presentation aid. These should include at least three
images that provide evidence for a clear assertion. They use
personal computers to create these presentation aids and share them
with the class when complete. Questions groups should answer in
front of the class include:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where did you find your images?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What did you find most challenging about this project?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do you think your visual aids do best?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What aspect of these visual aids could use the most improvement?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires a classroom computer, a projector, and Internet
access for demonstration. The students will need to bring their own
computers if the class does not have access to a computer lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
technology usage will present an unreasonable burden be accommodated on an
individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v0.01 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo Compatibility
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Presentation of Data</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-presentation-of-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/visual-presentation-of-data/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the most common types of charts and graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can create effective charts and graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand how to cite data in charts and graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify common errors in creating charts and graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students know what to consider before using existing charts and graphs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Presenting numerical data, such as statistical evidence
visually is one of the best uses of presentation aids. People can much
more easily understand data when it is presented in a visual format rather
than as a list of more abstract numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A computer with Internet access for demonstration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A board and markers/chalk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least one computer with Internet access per group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common graphs and charts

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tables&lt;/strong&gt; list raw numerical data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bar graphs&lt;/strong&gt; compare categories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pictograms&lt;/strong&gt; use a series of images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pie graphs&lt;/strong&gt; display portions of a whole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Line graphs&lt;/strong&gt; display changes over time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cartesian plots&lt;/strong&gt; show relationships between continuous variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Histograms&lt;/strong&gt; are simplified Cartesian plots displayed as a bar graph (without space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timelines&lt;/strong&gt; display the temporal relationships of different events&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating your own charts and graphs in PowerPoint

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common student errors in creating charts and graphs

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using tables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing the wrong type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-D effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not using direct labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unnecessary text (titles, scales, labels, keys)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Infographics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relying solely on semantic color&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:colorblind&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:colorblind&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students work in teams to locate create graphs and charts in PowerPoint. Students use US Mortality data located online from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nvss/deaths.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CDC&lt;/a&gt;. Students should create 3 assertion-evidence structure slides which use graphs and charts based on these data as their visual evidence. There should be one slide which uses a bar graph or histogram, a second which uses a pie graph, and a third which uses a line graph. They use personal computers to create these presentation aids and share them with the class when complete. Questions groups should answer in front of the class include:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What did you find most challenging about this project?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What aspect of these charts and graphs?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;How would you cite these data?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using existing charts and graphs is like using images

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aspect Ratio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backgrounds and Colors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Licensing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oral presentation of numerical data

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contextualize numbers for your audience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use round numbers unless precision is &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires a classroom computer, a projector, and Internet
access for demonstration. The students will need to bring their own
computers if the class does not have access to a computer lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom technology usage will present an unreasonable burden be accommodated on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:---------------
  v0.02 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo Compatibility
  v0.01 | 2017-10-03 | updated to include timelines and color vision deficiency numbers
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:colorblind&#34;&gt;Approximately 1 in 20 people (1 in 12 males and 1 in 200 females) have some form of color vision deficiency.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:colorblind&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crisis Response Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/crisis-response-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/crisis-response-presentations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the principles of a good crisis response presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand common mistakes made in crisis response presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students experience producing a crisis response presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; The speed of information has increased dramatically in our
interconnected world. Social media, blogging, and other forms of
communication technology mean that crises appear and build momentum more
quickly than ever. Basic exposure to crisis response presentations is
essential because members of organizations never know when they may need
to be part of responding to a crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 printed “disaster memos” or sets of instructions (B Horror Movies work well)

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090837/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chopping Mall&lt;/em&gt; IMDb Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1034314/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Iron Sky&lt;/em&gt; IMDb Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0095444/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Killer Klowns from Outer Space&lt;/em&gt; IMDb Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0090094/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Stuff&lt;/em&gt; IMDb Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082910/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Piranha Part Two: The Spawning&lt;/em&gt; IMDb Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion about current crises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principles of Crisis Presentations

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Know Your Place&lt;/strong&gt; (what can you say? where should you direct?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timely Response&lt;/strong&gt; (maintain control of the narrative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accurate Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Focused&lt;/strong&gt; (talking doesn&amp;rsquo;t solve problems alone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider Multiple Audiences&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regulators / Law Enforcement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Errors in Crisis Communication

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;No Comment&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking &amp;ldquo;Off the Record&amp;rdquo; (no legal requirement for confidence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speculation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not being honest and responsive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being too proactive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accidentally admitting guilt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day-cc&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day-cc&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group students into 5 groups of 3-4 students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group selects or is assigned a disaster envelope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups have 30 minutes to research their topic and prepare a 2 minute presentation

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This presentation must use a presentation aid similar in style to a PowerPoint presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each member in the group must participate in the presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students are encouraged to leave the classroom to collaborate during this portion of the assignment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group delivers its presentation, which is followed by a brief Question and Answer session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires student access to online resources and personal computers. Strategic grouping may be necessary for improved peer mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom technology usage will present an unreasonable burden may be accommodated on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|---------------
  v0.03 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo Compatibility
  v0.02 |          - | Minor text fixes
  v0.01 |          - | Added links to IMDb articles for B Horror Movies
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day&#34;&gt;Pruim, D. E. (2016). Disaster Day! Integrating speech skills through impromptu group research and presentation. &lt;em&gt;Communication Teacher&lt;/em&gt;, 30(2), 62-66. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17404622.2016.1139148&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17404622.2016.1139148&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day-cc&#34;&gt;Pruim, D. E. (2016). Instructor’s corner: Disaster Day! An impromptu group speech activity. &lt;em&gt;Communication Currents&lt;/em&gt;, 11(3). Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.natcom.org/CommCurrentsArticle.aspx?id=7114&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.natcom.org/CommCurrentsArticle.aspx?id=7114&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:Pruim-2016-Disaster-Day-cc&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbal and Nonverbal Delivery</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/verbal-and-nonverbal-delivery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/verbal-and-nonverbal-delivery/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the features of good verbal delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the features of good nonverbal delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students come out of their shell and present passionately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; The speed of information has increased dramatically in our
interconnected world. Social media, blogging, and other forms of
communication technology mean that crises appear and build momentum more
quickly than ever. Basic exposure to crisis response presentations is
essential because members of organizations never know when they may need
to be part of responding to a crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View Phil Davison speech&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:phil-davison&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:phil-davison&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivery matters

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t look like you care, why should your audience care?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boring presentations are the worst&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:at-least-bad-is-interesting&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:at-least-bad-is-interesting&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using note cards

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write on one side only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use only key words, not full sentences (except references and direct quotes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start each new entry on a new line&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Treat them as a &amp;ldquo;checklist&amp;rdquo; to make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t forget something or jump around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring the cards up! Do not bring your face down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include additional information (reminders, positive talk, delivery cues)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider using colors to highlight transitions or other important parts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mistakes to avoid:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not using normal 3x5 index cards (unless you are a giant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using tiny scraps of paper as note cards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using brightly colored note cards (difficult to see, and distract your audience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing your entire presentation on them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filling note cards with text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do with my hands.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Throwing note cards when done with them (distracts your audience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading them off of a table/podium (the whole point is that they can move with you)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verbal Delivery

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pitch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vocal variety&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fillers and fluency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonverbal Delivery

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whole body movement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Posture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gestures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adapters&lt;/strong&gt; (generally distracting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facial Expressions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eye contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go create an outline for a brief presentation in groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice delivering it individually

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each member should have a different verbal and nonverbal style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over-enthusiasm is encouraged&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliver the random presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires student access to online resources and personal
computers. Strategic grouping may be necessary for improved peer
mentoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
technology usage will present an unreasonable burden may be accommodated
on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if
needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|:--------------
  v0.04 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.03 | 2017-09-14 | Expanded on note card section, Added facial expressions (how did I forget those?)
  v0.02 | 2017-08-11 | Added section on using note cards
  v0.01 | 2017-03-09 | Corrected link in footnote
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:phil-davison&#34;&gt;Gebhardt, S. (2011, March 8). &amp;ldquo;Phil Davison, GOP Candidate [Original, Full Video]&amp;rdquo; [Online Video]. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/djfDZrm9KZs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://youtu.be/djfDZrm9KZs&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:phil-davison&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:at-least-bad-is-interesting&#34;&gt;There is nothing worse than a boring presentation. At least bad presentations are memorable.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:at-least-bad-is-interesting&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing Persuasive Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-persuasive-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/organizing-persuasive-presentations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify each of the common persuasive organization
schemes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand common mistakes for each organization scheme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify each of the stages in Monroe&amp;rsquo;s Motivated Sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can create a presentation using Monroe&amp;rsquo;s Motivated Sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Using a recognizable organization pattern through all of
the main points in a presentation makes it easier for the audience to
follow the presentation. Considering multiple organization patterns for
a topic often highlights different and more compelling approaches to the
presentation, and often more effective main points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approximately 5 mundane objects that can be repurposed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion about the need for organization patterns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Persuasive Organization Patterns

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-sided&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-sided&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-sided Refutative&lt;/strong&gt; (avoid straw man arguments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-Solution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-Cause-Solution&lt;/strong&gt; (when how the solution impacts the problem is not clear)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monroe&amp;rsquo;s Motivated Sequence&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attention (in the introduction)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Satisfaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visualization (your better life now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Call to Action (in the conclusion [usually the clincher])&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video examples of Monroe&amp;rsquo;s Motivated Sequence

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MyMzYjXPMA0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tater Mitts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6e3z2H1O5zE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EZ Cracker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing effective patterns

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audience analysis (psychological profile)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environmental analysis (time available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hands-on group work

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students are divided into groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups are given a mundane object and asked to come up with an alternate use for this object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups work together to prepare an impromptu presentation that uses Monroe&amp;rsquo;s Motivated Sequence to &amp;ldquo;sell&amp;rdquo; this object for the alternative use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual students from each group present their presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson requires random mundane objects and student creativity.
Displaying examples requires a classroom computer and a video projector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. You may ask students
to identify and exchange their own random mundane objects that they
brought with them rather than providing the objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions:

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|---------------
  v0.01 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Special Occasion Presentations</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/special-occasion-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/special-occasion-presentations/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the purposes of special occasion presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students know the most common types of special occasion presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand key requirements for success in these presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students experience delivering unprepared special occasion
presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Many of the presentation opportunities that we encounter
occur during special occasions. Many types of special occasion speech can
occur without warning, so a basic familiarity is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blank paper for certificates (1 per student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crayons/markers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion about special occasion presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purposes of Special Occasion Presentations &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:OHair&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:OHair&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entertainment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Celebration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commemoration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspiration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting an Agenda or Theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Special Occasion Presentations &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:OHair&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:OHair&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speech of Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acceptance Speeches&lt;/strong&gt; (remember those who gave the award)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speeches of Presentation&lt;/strong&gt; (discuss both award &amp;amp; recipient)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toasts and Roasts&lt;/strong&gt; (Brevity!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eulogies&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotion is ok and expected! Remain in control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember the family&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Positive, but realistic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dinner Speeches&lt;/strong&gt; (discuss occasion and group)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inspirational Speeches&lt;/strong&gt; (Clincher! Clincher! Clincher!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome to the Speech 101 Awards!

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students divide into groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each group has 5 minutes to brainstorm awards to give to each of the members of a second group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group members have 10 minutes to prepare short, 1-2 minute speeches of presentation for the award. These awards can be as serious or as silly as students like. They should also make a certificate!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individual group members present their awards. Award winners deliver unprepared speeches of acceptance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debrief the activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lesson only provides students with experience with two of the many
different types of special occasion presentation. Some students have
a difficult time coming up with awards for class members who are very
quiet. Keep an eye out for mean-spirited awards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
Debrief
=======
--&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom
using paper and writing utensils to create an award certificate presents
an unreasonable burden will be accommodated on an individual basis.
Students may be placed in groups strategically if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- End Notes --&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions

   v#   | Date       | Modifications
  ------|------------|---------------
  v0.01 | 2019-08-07 | Changes for Hugo compatibility
  v0.00 |          - | Initial Version

--&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:OHair&#34;&gt;O’Hair, D., Stewart, R. A., &amp;amp; Rubenstein, H. (2015). &lt;em&gt;A speaker’s guidebook: Text and reference&lt;/em&gt; (6th ed.). Boston: Bedford/St. Martin’s.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:OHair&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graded PowerPoint Rubric</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/graded-powerpoint-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/graded-powerpoint-rubric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The graded PowerPoint portion of this assignment is worth 25 points. (Yes,
you get a sneaky bonus point! Shh, it&amp;rsquo;s not a math class!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Supports the Presentation&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses a variety of types of visual evidence to support assertions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses visual evidence to support assertions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Majority of slides are text only.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No visual evidence included.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Professional&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The visual aid has a unified visual style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fonts, colors, and presentation of visual evidence are consistent on most slides.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Fonts, colors, and presentation of visual evidence are inconsistent.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Contents of slides are inappropriate for professional use.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References and Citations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations and complete reference information for all evidence in the visual in APA format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations included for most evidence in the visual aid. Complete reference information included.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Majority of evidence is missing citation &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; reference information.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citation &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing throughout visual aid.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Accessible&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that are accessible and appropriate for a general audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that hinder usability for some audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses fonts, font sizes, and colors that hinder usability for average audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Significant problems with accessibility. Slides not useful for average audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Formatted&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;All content slides use Assertion-Evidence structure.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;One error in Assertion-Evidence structure appears on one content slide.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;One error in Assertion-Evidence structure appears on multiple content slides.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Content slides have multiple errors of many kinds.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Evidence with citation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing is plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outline Rubric</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/outline-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/outline-rubric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The outline portion of this assignment is worth 25 points. (Yes, you get
a sneaky bonus point! Shh, it&amp;rsquo;s not a math class!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;4 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;3 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;2 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;1 point&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Voice&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written as the presenter would speak to the audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in complete sentences, but not in a spoken style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline has occasional sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline is written in sentence fragments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Complete and effective introduction, supported main points, and conclusion, all separated by effective transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction, supported main points, or conclusion are ineffective. All transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of introduction or conclusion incomplete. Supported main points. Some transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sections or transitions are missing or main points are not supported.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline Principles&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline follows the principles of parallelism, coordination, subordination, and division.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks one of the outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks no more than two outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Outline breaks multiple outline principles.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;In-text Citations&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and mostly written how they will be said during the presentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are all present and are written using APA/MLA style.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Citations are not present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Reference Section&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly and in APA format.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed properly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are listed, but have errors.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;References are not listed or are listed incorrectly.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Format&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Uses a professional 12 point font, double spaced. Effective and consistent numbering and indentation.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one minor inconsistency in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No more than one major inconsistency or two minor inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Multiple inconsistencies in formatting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Evidence with citation &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; reference information missing is plagiarism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Rubric</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/presentation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/handout/presentation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The presentation portion of this assignment is worth 100 points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;20 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;15 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;10 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;5 points&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Topic Fit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is compelling and interesting for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is appropriate for the environment or audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The topic is inappropriate for the environment and audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is compelling and adds to the presentation. Complete and effective introduction, conclusion, and transitions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Organization is clear. Complete introduction and conclusion. Transitions present.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Portions of organization unclear. Portions of introduction or conclusion missing. One transition missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;No organization clear to audience. Significant problems with introduction or conclusion. Transitions missing.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points are effectively supported. Evidence cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and main points supported. Most evidence is cited completely and appropriately.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis not supported by main points or support for main points missing. Citations for evidence are incomplete.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thesis and/or main points missing. No citations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Delivery&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Verbally fluent and nonverbally engaging.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Minor issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would not distract a general audience.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Distracting issues with verbal or nonverbal delivery that would distract many audience members.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Significant delivery issues that prevent even motivated audience members from understanding.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Time Management&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 30 seconds of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 1 minute of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation is within 2 minutes of target length.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Presentation significantly short or had to be stopped.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logical Fallacies</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/logical-fallacies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/logical-fallacies/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persuasion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interpersonal Communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Argument and Debate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differentiate between a logical fallacy and a logical booby-trap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand the difference between formal and informal fallacies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name several common fallacies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize these fallacies and booby-traps in the real world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Students are constantly exposed to persuasive messages in the real world. Many of these messages promote logically flawed reasoning or contain logically flawed arguments. Creating and evaluating persuasive messages is a keystone skill in our field. Persuasive speeches are fundamental components of the basic course in communication, and most communication departments offer semester-long classes on persuasion. Persuasive messages which employ or promote fallacious reasoning may be less effective, and can be considered unethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A classroom projector and computer for any video examples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion about logical fallacies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of logical fallacies

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Propositional fallacies

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affirming the Consequent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denying the Antecedent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affirming a Disjunct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commutation of Conditionals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probabilistic fallacies

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Base Rate fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Gambler&amp;rsquo;s fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hot Hand fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple Comparisons fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bad Reasons fallacies

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The conclusion must be wrong because the argument was bad.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fallacist&amp;rsquo;s fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red Herring fallacies

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straw Person&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Genetic fallacy (Ad Hominem)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bandwagon fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Two wrongs make a right&amp;rdquo; (Tu Quoque)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appeal to Consequences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appeal to Emotion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guilt by Association&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vagueness fallacies

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slippery Slope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;False Precision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non causa pro causa

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cum hoc, ergo propter hoc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post hoc, ergo propter hoc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regression fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Texas Sharpshooter fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weak analogies

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unrepresentative sample&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hasty Generalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Question Begging

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loaded Words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Naturalistic fallacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;False Dilemma&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Activity&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:gift-2015&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:gift-2015&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 1

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduce key concepts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Students will need to understand the following key concepts: premise, argument, fallacy, validity, testimony, formal fallacy, and informal fallacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The instructor demonstrates how fallacies and logical booby-traps work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The naturalistic fallacy works well. Many products are advertised as “natural” or “all natural.” Students readily understand once it is pointed out that things which &lt;strong&gt;are not&lt;/strong&gt; natural &lt;strong&gt;can&lt;/strong&gt; be good (examples: a classroom education, riding a bicycle, sunscreen), and some things which &lt;strong&gt;are&lt;/strong&gt; natural are dangerous anyway (examples: arsenic, tobacco, poison ivy, mountain lions). &lt;em&gt;Caution: Avoid using products where naturalness is logically relevant, such as food products, as this is not fallacious reasoning. Cleaning products are good choices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assign students a fallacy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Students pick a fallacy from a larger typology of common fallacies&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:curtis-2013-lf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:curtis-2013-lf&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; or are assigned one. If students pick their own fallacies, the instructor should ensure that common fallacies are not excluded. Common fallacies include the hasty generalization, false dilemma, weak analogy, slippery slope, the naturalistic fallacy, and post/cum hoc ergo propter hoc fallacies. The red herring family of fallacies (ad hominem, bandwagon, straw person, appeal to misleading authority, etc.) is also common.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Between Classes:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students identify examples outside of class.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Students may use print advertisements or video examples. Videos should be less than one minute long (most advertisements meet this easily). Students should not use examples that require long blocks of text. The example can be an example of a logical fallacy (an argument), or an example of a logical booby-trap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Day 2:

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Students show the examples they found.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Students show the examples that they found in class and explain why the argument is fallacious. If your room has a projector and document camera, you can use this to display print examples for full class analysis. This is a good time to talk about the distinctions between formal and informal fallacies, which helps students distinguish between an argument’s form and its content. It is also a good time to talk about the difference between fallacies, which contain an explicit argument, and logical booby-traps, which do not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The activity requires two different classroom days to devote to this assignment. The activity requires a classroom projector and computer for video examples. The activity can be completed without these, if students do not bring video examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;debrief&#34;&gt;Debrief&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of students will find decent examples of fallacies. Some will come back with good examples of fallacies, just not examples of the fallacies they were assigned. This is ok, and is a good opportunity to talk about how some fallacies are related conceptually. You may not have time to show all of the examples during class, particularly if they are videos that students can only find again by clicking on a link they e-mailed to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign for credit or extra credit through the semester. Cap the number of examples you will accept for each fallacy. This works well in a persuasion class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include a short paper where the student analyzes and corrects the flawed argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have students identify the fallacies in teams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;lesson-plan-version&#34;&gt;Lesson Plan Version&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently v0.01&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A previous version of the activity from this lesson plan was competitively selected for presentation at a conference.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:gift-2015&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:gift-2015&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Previous Versions
  v0.01 | Corrected numbering errors
  v0.00 | Initial Version
--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-notes&#34;&gt;End Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:gift-2015&#34;&gt;Miller, K. D. (2015). Converging in class with examples of fallacies and logical booby-traps from real life persuasive messages. Presented at the Annual Meeting of the Central States Communication Association, Madison, WI.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:gift-2015&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:curtis-2013-lf&#34;&gt;Curtis, G., N. (2013). Logical fallacies: The fallacy files. Retrieved October 01, 2014, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fallacyfiles.org/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://www.fallacyfiles.org/index.html&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:curtis-2013-lf&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persuasive Targets, Effects, and Appeals</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/persuasive-targets-effects-and-appeals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/persuasive-targets-effects-and-appeals/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify each of the four persuasive targets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify each of the three ways to effect persuasive targets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify and use each of the three types of persuasive appeals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; Persuasive presentations are goal directed. Creating effective persuasive presentations requires an understanding of what changes you intend to effect in your audience and how you intend to accomplish them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Todo: * Approximately 5 mundane objects that can be repurposed --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion about persuasion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persuasive Targets

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behaviors (easiest to change, most peripheral to identity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attitudes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beliefs (hardest to change, most central to identity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persuasive Effects

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reinforce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing Persuasive Targets and Effects

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your objective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audience analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persuasive Appeals

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types of appeal

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logos (Logic)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethos (Credibility)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pathos (Emotion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should work to strengthen all three appeals in a persuasive presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Todo: Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- Todo: This lesson is currently just a lecture with no application. --&gt;

&lt;!-- ### Debrief --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;variations-and-accommodations&#34;&gt;Variations and Accommodations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;!-- Todo: Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom technology usage will present an unreasonable burden be accommodated on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if needed. --&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;lesson-plan-version&#34;&gt;Lesson Plan Version&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently v0.00
&lt;!-- Previous Versions
  v0.00 | Initial Version
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ## End Notes --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting in a Team</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/presenting-in-a-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/lesson-plan/presenting-in-a-team/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course(s) Used:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small Group Communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals and Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students can identify the principles of a good crisis response presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students understand common mistakes made in crisis response presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students experience producing a crisis response presentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationale:&lt;/strong&gt; The speed of information has increased dramatically in our interconnected world. Social media, blogging, and other forms of communication technology mean that crises appear and build momentum more quickly than ever. Basic exposure to crisis response presentations is essential because members of organizations never know when they may need to be part of responding to a crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;materials-needed&#34;&gt;Materials Needed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom computer and projector&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outline-of-the-lesson&#34;&gt;Outline of the Lesson&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review of previous session&amp;rsquo;s content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson opening&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students share group work horror stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open classroom discussion group work and group presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Principles of effective group presentations

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything that is part of a good individual presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assign roles and tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use deadlines and make expectations clear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include transitions between speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about what you are doing when you are not speaking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your group members according to their strengths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coordinate presentation aids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehearse together several times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common Problems that Groups Encounter

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Toxic group members&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disagreement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No plan for missing group members (includes presentation aids)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groupthink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of enthusiasm or differing goals
&lt;!-- Todo: activity --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lesson closing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- ### Limitations

This lesson requires student access to online resources and personal computers. Strategic grouping may be necessary for improved peer mentoring.
--&gt;

&lt;!-- ### Debrief --&gt;

&lt;!--
### Variations and Accommodations

Follow guidance from local accommodation authorities. Students for whom technology usage will present an unreasonable burden may be accommodated on an individual basis. Students may be placed in groups strategically if needed.
--&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;lesson-plan-version&#34;&gt;Lesson Plan Version&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently v0.00
&lt;!-- Previous Versions
  v0.00 | Initial Version
--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ## End Notes --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
