<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debate Team Practicum</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/debate-practicum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/debate-practicum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- course description --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Students will prepare for and compete in public speaking, debate, and/or dramatic interpretation events as part of the Debate team. Emphasis will be given to discussion of current issues. Students who are active in debate learn many important skills which can serve them throughout their professional lives. Travel to at least one competitive event will be required, as well as a fee to offset competition entrance fees, transportation costs, and other expenses. Students may not take COMM 220 Argumentation and Debate and this course for credit in the same semester. Offered every semester. (May be repeated for up to 8 credits).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpersonal Communication</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/interpersonal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/interpersonal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- course description --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Description:&lt;/strong&gt; This course examines the current thory and
research traditions in the areas of interpersonal communication. Topics in
the course will include scripted and role-based interaction, intimate
relationships and relationship development, deception, verbal and
nonverbal aspects of communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--

## Resources

   * [Citations in Presentation Aids][]
   * [Oral Citations in Presentations][]
 * [Consent to Use Student Work][]

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/public-speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- course description --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Description:&lt;/strong&gt; Speaking clearly and comfortably in public is an essential skill set. This course prepares students for a variety of professional situations in which formal presentations are expected. Topics will include cultural conventions of speech, verbal and nonverbal messaging, and techniques of oral presentation and persuasion. Students will learn to research, outline, and deliver a variety of speeches (e.g. demonstrative, informative, persuasive, special occasion, etc.) of varying lengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--

## Resources

   * [Citations in Presentation Aids][]
   * [Oral Citations in Presentations][]
 * [Consent to Use Student Work][]

--&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debate Team Practicum</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/course/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
