<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>debate on Kurtis D. Miller</title>
    <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/debate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in debate on Kurtis D. Miller</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year}, Kurtis D. Miller, some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://kurtisdmiller.com/tags/debate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tusculum Debate at the Spring Sensation, 2018</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/tusculum-debate-at-the-spring-sensation-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/tusculum-debate-at-the-spring-sensation-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;100%&#34; src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/debate/2018-03-31-debate-at-nescc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;River and Alex with debate coach Dr. Miller&#34; title=&#34;River and Alex with debate coach Dr. Miller&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Andrew Johnson Debate Team at Tusculum had another strong showing over the Easter weekend. Alex Rolison (Senior, Museum Studies) and River Donnelly (Sophomore, Psychology) finished in 5th place at the 12th annual Spring Sensation tournament at Northeast State Community College in Blountville, TN. There were 13 pairings representing 6 schools at this competition. Alex and River had only one loss during the round-robin portion of the tournament, but finished just outside the top four pairings, who went on to the elimination phase of the tournament. This is a very impressive finish considering that this tournament is only the second competition since the club was founded this Spring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tusculum Debate at the Tennessee Valley Invitational, 2018</title>
      <link>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/tusculum-debate-at-the-tennessee-valley-invitational-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kurtisdmiller.com/post/tusculum-debate-at-the-tennessee-valley-invitational-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&#34;100%&#34; src=&#34;https://kurtisdmiller.com/img/debate/28500112_10216226244717775_676967098_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Evan and Alex with debate coach Dr. Miller&#34; title=&#34;Evan and Alex with debate coach Dr. Miller&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Andrew Johnson Debate Team at Tusculum competed in the Tennessee Valley Invitational at Pellissippi State Community College in Knoxville on Saturday, February 24th. This multi-state tournament was the debut event for competitive debate at Tusculum, and included over 40 students from across the region. Our team of Evan Altizer and Alex Rolison made a successful debut in the novice division, and received several compliments from competitors and coaches at established programs. The team was very competitive in the round-robin portion of the tournament. During the round robin the team made a strong showing against several other teams, including narrow losses to the teams which went on to win 1st and 2nd in the division.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
